<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
	<channel>
		<title>Zachary Yaro's Blog-Like News Feed</title>
		<link>https://zmyaro.com/blog</link>
		<description>Information about updates on zmyaro.com</description>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 12:30:00 EST</pubDate>
		<copyright>Zachary Yaro</copyright>
		<!-- <item>
			<title></title>
			<link>https://zmyaro.com/blog/</link>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[
				]]>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 00 Jan 2021 00:00:00 EST</pubDate>
		</item> -->
		<item>
			<title>MaterialZ v2.y</title>
			<link>https://zmyaro.com/blog/2021-05-04</link>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[
					<img src="https://zmyaro.com/blog/2021-05-04/mz_banner.svg" style="max-width: 100%; display: block; margin: 0 auto;" alt="MaterialZ." />
					<p>
						The next version of <a href="https://zmyaro.com/misc/materialz">MaterialZ</a> is now rolling out: Version&mdash;um...OK, so version numbers in the last few MaterialZ updates have been a little bit...undefined.  Solution: I dub the now-previous version &ldquo;2.x&rdquo;, and that makes this new release <strong>MaterialZ v2.y</strong>!  And it has been packed with exciting things (well, exciting if you like plug-and-play Material Design CSS libraries), ranging from support for some newer browser features (like <code>prefers-reduced-motion</code>), to long-wanted features (like toggle switches and checkbox ripples), to the occasional overdue fix for an older browser (shout-out to anyone else still keeping an Android 2.x device alive).
					</p>
					<p>
						Even with all that, though, it maintains the original goal of MaterialZ: Drop it into an unstyled page for instant Material-ization&mdash;it &ldquo;just works&rdquo;.  And to be sure the new features work as expected in real use cases (and to flex a little on the number of Google apps that still do not use Google's official Material Web Components library), I pretty much updated
						<a href="https://github.com/ZMYaro/paintz/commit/27effb18322d75aeb228e7e7260cb2a222b544cb" target="_blank">all</a>
						<a href="https://github.com/ZMYaro/dr-magnethands/commit/8c97caaf5299384f0a8daadd5ab6c9c10927f50e" target="_blank">my</a>
						<a href="https://github.com/ZMYaro/tetrescape/commit/c63c8af7390285280142956cae84a792f4d90857" target="_blank">MaterialZ</a>
						<a href="https://github.com/ZMYaro/sentiment-visualizer/commit/2094ab8b09c1940e54e3351d0e06bfafb98dd782" target="_blank">apps</a>
						to the new version&mdash;<!--
						--><a href="https://github.com/ZMYaro/earz/commit/fbe28d9d49fd4367b6c7c193729f625bdcc5342f" target="_blank">old</a>
						<a href="https://github.com/ZMYaro/neighborz/commit/bb758f2eae0ea0c1442bc3397dea97a3a010118f" target="_blank">ones</a>;
						<a href="https://github.com/ZMYaro/groceriez/commit/5b428892e7af2d35248375478b3a2ad4c0c169e2" target="_blank">personal</a>
						<a href="https://github.com/ZMYaro/right-vs-happy/commit/4d25e7c5770e9694e9cd01da937e54339c9fa152" target="_blank">ones</a>;
						even
						<a href="https://github.com/ZMYaro/fourier/commit/6ae402c58cd0490e9af03ce9ff2a9e6176e5db43" target="_blank">the</a>
						<a href="https://github.com/ZMYaro/poi-move-generator/commit/51013e108dba227183b2cdd083c77d8107b74017" target="_blank">random</a>
						<a href="https://github.com/ZMYaro/republican-response-generator/commit/7f31dbb72c15645ae1175736758d5a43f7e8e1f6" target="_blank">tiny</a>
						<a href="https://github.com/ZMYaro/bday-quilt/commit/bab0e5d0ef2a0407a44dfe6026496988557b5a50" target="_blank">silly</a>
						<a href="https://github.com/ZMYaro/rupaul-game/commit/770827039e0933c319f3c4a5d3612328b0428fcc" target="_blank">ones</a>.
						Oh, and some got the new plug-and-play
						<a href="https://github.com/ZMYaro/groceriez/commit/a6bd7aeb318ebce732f2339a9ef5c1a5bdf7dd72" target="_blank">dark</a>
						<a href="https://github.com/ZMYaro/right-vs-happy/commit/4d25e7c5770e9694e9cd01da937e54339c9fa152" target="_blank">theme</a>
						too.
						(Granted, most of those are almost infinitely less complex than your average Google app, but the point is I think it works &#x1f61c;)
					</p>
					<p>
						You can check out all the new stuff at <a href="https://materialz.dev" target="_blank">MaterialZ.dev</a>.  If you want to support my dev work, consider backing <a href="https://patreon.com/ZMYaro" target="_blank">my Patreon</a> <small>(egh, does that ever feel less weird to say?)</small> or <a href="https://ko-fi.com/ZMYaro" target="_blank">buying me a Ko-fi</a>.  And here are the release notes for v2.y:
					</p>
					<ul>
						<li>Added dark theme</li>
						<li>Added toggle switches</li>
						<li>Added support for date, date/time, month, telephone, time, and week inputs</li>
						<li>Added ripple around checkboxes and radio buttons</li>
						<li>Added full-width card class</li>
						<li>Added ability to set accent color via custom property</li>
						<li>Made more elements derive their theme colors from their <code>color</code>s</li>
						<li>Made unchecked checkboxes and radio buttons match their surrounding text color</li>
						<li>Disabled animations when <code>prefers-reduced-motion</code> is set to <code>reduce</code></li>
						<li>Increased default card corner radius to 3px</li>
						<li>Slightly reduced padding on <code>&lt;select&gt;</code> drop-down arrows</li>
						<li>Fixed radio buttons, slider thumbs, and circular progress spinners appearing square on old Android browsers</li>
						<li>Removed Internet Explorer fallback lines from <code>material-depth.css</code></li>
						<li>Removed suggestion to set circular progress spinners' <code>border-top-color</code>s</li>
						<li>Improved demo page (in addition to updating it to include the new features)</li>
					</ul>
					<p style="font-style: italic;">
						Also posted to <a href="https://www.facebook.com/ZMYaro/posts/4053181351369713" target="_blank">Facebook</a>, <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/COdP0wrrHEA/" target="_blank">Instagram</a>, and <a href="https://twitter.com/ZMYaro/status/1389610384869498881" target="_blank">Twitter</a>.
					</p>
				]]>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 12:30:00 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Some Smaller App Improvements (And A Shout-Out To A Friend)</title>
			<link>https://zmyaro.com/blog/2021-02-14</link>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[
					<p>
						One small thing not really worthy of its own post, but you may have noticed <a href="https://zmyaro.com/extensions/discordtouch">Touch-Friendliness for Discord</a> was broken by the last Discord redesign.  The good news is that redesign addressed several issues the extension was initially created to fix, so there are fewer places the extension needs to step in, which is always kind of the hope with accessibility extensions.  The newer good news is an update is rolling out that makes the extension compatible with the current version of Discord, so everything their redesign did <em>not</em> address is touch-friendly again.
					</p>
					<p>
						Unrelated to that, I have mentioned this before on my social media, but <a href="https://okay.wasv.me" target="_blank">Okay</a> by Billie Stevens is a great lightweight app to have to deal with high stress, panic attacks, or the like.  I submitted a small update to it last week so you can now install it to your home screen and use it offline.
					</p>
					<figure>
						<a href="https://zmyaro.com/blog/2021-02-14/okay_scrnsht.png" target="_blank">
							<img src="https://zmyaro.com/blog/2021-02-14/okay_scrnsht.png" alt="A screenshot of okay dot wasv dot me says, Are you okay?  Let's Check.  At the bottom, a browser prompt says, Add Okay to Home screen." style="max-width: 100%; max-height: 600px;" />
						</a>
					</figure>
					<p style="font-style: italic;">
						Okay update also posted to <a href="https://www.facebook.com/ZMYaro/posts/3823868157634368" target="_blank">Facebook</a>, <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CLRFaqfrg5B" target="_blank">Instagram</a>, and <a href="https://twitter.com/ZMYaro/status/1360876022648995842" target="_blank">Twitter</a>.
					</p>
				]]>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 05:00:00 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Patreon</title>
			<link>https://zmyaro.com/blog/2021-02-09</link>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[
					<p>
						Over the past few years, I have experimented with a few ways for people to &ldquo;buy me a coffee&rdquo; to support my free apps.  This year, I am trying out Patreon.  I totally recognize a lot of folks are not in a position to donate to open-source software right now, but the start of a new year seemed like a good time to flip the switch.
					</p>
					<p>
						As with past experiments, this is not a paywall. At a future point, when things feel a little less up in the air, I might try more of its features beyond giving folks a way to help cover the costs of developing and hosting these apps, but everything available now and all the core features I was already planning to add to PaintZ, Voice Actions, MaterialZ, Magnethands, etc. will remain free forever.
					</p>
					<p>
						<a href="https://patreon.com/ZMYaro" target="_blank">&#x27a1; patreon.com/ZMYaro</a>
					</p>
					<p style="font-style: italic;">
						Also posted to <a href="https://www.facebook.com/ZMYaro/posts/3811018495586001" target="_blank">Facebook</a>, <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CLEPdoarPoQ" target="_blank">Instagram</a>, and <a href="https://twitter.com/ZMYaro/status/1359070661218598913" target="_blank">Twitter</a>.
					</p>
				]]>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 05:00:00 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Rewind Theater Update</title>
			<link>https://zmyaro.com/blog/2021-01-27</link>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[
					<a href="https://zmyaro.com/blog/2021-01-27/bowsers_fury_rewind_theater.png" target="_blank">
						<img src="https://zmyaro.com/blog/2021-01-27/bowsers_fury_rewind_theater_small.png" alt="Cat elements are highlighted in the trailer for Bowser's Fury using the Rewind Theater app." />
					</a>
					<p>
						<a href="https://zmyaro.com/apps/rewindtheater">Rewind Theater</a> is a simple app based on the old IGN series of the same name, in which they scrubbed through trailers and highlighted details likely to be missed on a first viewing.  I threw the initial app together in under 48 hours before an event where we did a live analysis of the <i>Doctor Who</i> 50th anniversary trailers in 2013, but this month, I rolled out a variety of features and improvements that did not make it in by that deadline, including a nicer toolbar, new controls, better video loading times, offline functionality, and more.  <a href="https://rewindtheater.zmyaro.com" target="_blank">https://rewindtheater.zmyaro.com</a>
					</p>
					<p style="font-style: italic;">
						Also posted to <a href="https://www.facebook.com/ZMYaro/posts/3777793725575145" target="_blank">Facebook</a>, <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CKi6R2lrrNe" target="_blank">Instagram</a>, and <a href="https://twitter.com/ZMYaro/status/1354379083233308673" target="_blank">Twitter</a>.
					</p>
				]]>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 05:51:00 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>My Eyes! (Light Theme)</title>
			<link>https://zmyaro.com/blog/2021-01-15</link>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[
					<p>
						If you have heard me talk about web dev in the past couple years, one thing you might have heard me be very excited about is the <a href="https://web.dev/prefers-color-scheme" target="_blank"><code>prefers-color-scheme</code> media query</a>, which lets your site automatically follow the user's system (or browser) dark/light theme setting.  You might have also heard me complain about how few big-name apps support it (Google, please stop killing my eyes at night with your bright white everywhere).  But not to be a pot calling their kettle...not black...I have also been adding <code>prefers-color-scheme</code> detection to some of my apps, including <a href="https://zmyaro.com/apps/paintz">PaintZ</a>, <a href="https://zmyaro.com/extensions/voiceactions">Voice Actions for Chrome</a>, <a href="https://zmyaro.com/games/magnethands">Dr. Magnethands</a>, and I even added it to the deprecated <a href="https://zmyaro.com/misc/holo">Holo Web site</a>.
					</p>
					<p>
						However, there is a flipside: while dark themes are the ones most sought after to save our eyes as we work way too late into the evening (*glances nervously at the timestamp on this post*), light themes are far more readable in bright daylight, so I have, begrudgingly, talked myself into adding a light theme to my personal website.  If you visit <a href="https://zmyaro.com">zmyaro.com</a> from a browser that supports color scheme detection, and your system/browser is set to light theme, you will automatically get the brand new first iteration of it.  It is still a bit of a work in progress, but I hope this convinces web devs around the world (or, at least, in the offices of Google and parts of Facebook), if I can find a way to take my lovingly crafted dark theme and accommodate folks who prefer to browse the Internet in direct sunlight, perhaps you could make your styles a little easier on my eyes at 2:30 in the morning?
					</p>
					<p style="font-size: smaller;">
						(Also, while this was not a priority for a low-traffic personal website, it is worth noting the <em>best</em> user experience is to detect the prefered color scheme by default and then provide an option to override just for your app.  PaintZ, for instance, supports this.)
					</p>
					<br />
					<p>
						On a side note, I want to once again thank <a href="https://github.com/Armin2208/Windows-Auto-Night-Mode" target="_blank">Windows 10 Auto Dark Mode by Armin2208</a>, which automatically switches your Windows system theme to light at sunrise and dark at sunset.  I highly recommend it if you are also impatient to see that feature built into Windows by default.
					</p>
					<p style="font-style: italic;">
						Also posted to <a href="https://www.facebook.com/ZMYaro/posts/3744500202237831" target="_blank">Facebook</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/ZMYaro/status/1350003950775382016" target="_blank">Twitter</a>.
					</p>
				]]>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 03:50:00 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Workshop Scramble Anniversary/COVID-19 Update</title>
			<link>https://zmyaro.com/blog/2020-12-25</link>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[
					<p>
						Can you believe <a href="https://zmyaro.com/games/wss" target="_blank"><i>Workshop Scramble</i></a> is 3 years old??  Neither could I, because it's only 2 years old; this year has just apparently destroyed my ability to calculate time.  Anyway, while a lot of inProd priorities had to shift due to *gestures vaguely at the state of the world right now*, I wanted to do something slightly positive at the end of the year, so <i>Scramble</i> is getting a free anniversary update that adds the COVID-19 relief workshop.  In <i>Workshop Scramble</i>'s spirit of helping people in need around holidays, this unranked mode links you to charities you can donate to after you finish playing so your impact can extend beyond the game world.
					</p>
					<p>
						Stay safe, take care, and see you with some new stuff in the new year 💝
					</p>
					<img src="covid19_present.png" style="width: 256px; max-width: 100%; display: block; margin: 0 auto;" alt="Gloves, swabs, sanitizer, and a mask fall into a Workshop Scramble present box." />
					<p class="xpost">
						Also posted to <a href="https://www.facebook.com/inProdGames/posts/3871393712880818" target="_blank">Facebook</a>, <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CJO_t2IgxSm" target="_blank">Instagram</a>, and <a href="https://twitter.com/inProdGames/status/1342569034332696579" target="_blank">Twitter</a>.
					</p>
				]]>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 15:50:00 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Dr. Magnethands Is Back!</title>
			<link>https://zmyaro.com/blog/</link>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[
					<img src="https://zmyaro.com/games/magnethands/imgs/card.png" style="max-width: 100%; display: block; margin: 0 auto;" alt="Doctor Magnethands title screen." />
					<p>
						Whether you are (hopefully safely) visiting family for Christmas, or staying in lockdown with flatmates, here's a new game you can play: <i>Dr. Magnethands</i>, the tabletop RPG for three or more drunk people, now available as a convenient phone app!
					</p>
					<p>
						If you're saying, &ldquo;Didn't you already make that in 2016?&rdquo; yes, but then Google killed a service that app needed to run.  Now, after a few years' hiatus, Dr. Magnethands is back with some new (Google-free) stuff under the hood, a couple new tricks (dark theme is go!), and ready for you to once again enjoy the simplest, least serious TTRPG you've ever played (alcohol optional).  Try it now at <a href="http://magnethands.fun" target="_blank">magnethands.fun</a>.
					</p>
					<p style="font-style: italic;">
						Also posted to <a href="https://www.facebook.com/ZMYaro/posts/3687850397902812" target="_blank">Facebook</a>, <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CJJWyh8Lm4I" target="_blank">Instagram</a>, and <a href="https://twitter.com/ZMYaro/status/1341775891383406593" target="_blank">Twitter</a>.
					</p>
				]]>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 10:50:00 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>PaintZ v3.2</title>
			<link>https://zmyaro.com/blog/2020-11-30</link>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[
					<img src="https://zmyaro.com/blog/2020-11-30/paintz_3_2.png" style="max-width: 100%; display: block; margin: 0 auto;" alt="PaintZ v3.2." />
					<p>
						It's Cyber Monday, and for the low, low price of free again, we have the brand new PaintZ v3.2!  What makes it different from v3.1.1?  Well...
					</p>
					<ul>
						<li>Added transparent selection option</li>
						<li>Text no longer rasterizes immediately when the text box loses focus</li>
						<li>Duplicated and pasted selections now appear at the top-left corner of the visible canvas</li>
						<li>Selecting the canvas pulls focus</li>
						<li>Added pointer coordinates on the bottom bar (in sufficiently wide windows)</li>
						<li>Added canvas gridlines option</li>
						<li>Added gray and brown to toolbar color palette</li>
						<li>Added more line width options</li>
						<li>Added more text size options</li>
						<li>Added keyboard shortcut (<kbd>Ctrl</kbd>+<kbd>Alt</kbd>+<kbd>0</kbd>) to reset zoom level to 100%</li>
						<li>Added support for numpad +/- for zoom in/out keyboard shortcuts</li>
						<li>Added little hints of color to previously-monochromatic buttons</li>
						<li>Added new styling to keyboard shortcut hints in dialog boxes</li>
						<li>Added slight animation when the top toolbar shrinks as the window is narrowed</li>
						<li>Added &ldquo;About&rdquo; page</li>
						<li>Added &ldquo;Privacy&rdquo; page</li>
						<li>Added service worker caching (with app cache fallback)</li>
						<li>Fixed not being able to copy/cut a freeform selection via keyboard shortcut or browser clipboard menu</li>
						<li>Fixed not being able to copy/cut text from dialog boxes</li>
						<li>Fixed some keyboard shortcuts not working when typing a zoom level</li>
						<li>Fixed not being able to use zoom keyboard shortcuts while editing text</li>
						<li>Fixed browser open/save dialogs opening on <kbd>Ctrl</kbd>+<kbd>O</kbd>/<kbd>S</kbd> instead of PaintZ's while editing text</li>
						<li>Fixed browser help opening on <kbd>F1</kbd> instead of PaintZ's while editing text</li>
						<li>Fixed clipboard manager listening to clipboard events too early</li>
						<li>Fixed pressing <kbd>X</kbd> adding an unnecessary global variable</li>
					</ul>
					<p>
						It's all rolling out now at <a href="https://paintz.app" target="_blank">paintz.app</a>!  As always, I remain thankful for everyone who uses PaintZ, and especially to a few folks who sent nice messages over this year of lockdown while I worked on v3.2.  This update was going to come either way, and so will v3.3 and v4.0, but those little reminders of how many people I will never know find this app helpful are really gratifying motivators, especially in this mess of a year.
					</p>
					<p>
						And, finally, of course, if you're feeling thankful, any support <a href="https://patreon.com/zmyaro" target="_blank">on <del>Ko-fi</del>Patreon</a> is also appreciated 🌼
					</p>
					<p style="font-style: italic;">
						Also posted to <a href="https://www.facebook.com/PaintZApp/posts/4202828923077318" target="_blank">Facebook</a>, <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CIOB6P0B-QG" target="_blank">Instagram</a>, and <a href="https://twitter.com/PaintZApp/status/1333418265373253638" target="_blank">Twitter</a>.
					</p>
				]]>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 11:00:00 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>PaintZ Users, Watch This Space...</title>
			<link>https://zmyaro.com/blog/2020-11-27</link>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[
					<img src="https://zmyaro.com/blog/2020-11-27/paintz_3x_loading.gif" style="max-width: 100%; display: block; margin: 0 auto;" alt="PaintZ v3 point something is loading." />
					<p>
						There is no PaintZ Black Friday event this year, but check back with this feed on Cyber Monday...👀
					</p>
					<p style="font-style: italic;">
						Also posted to <a href="https://www.facebook.com/PaintZApp/posts/4194742437219300" target="_blank">Facebook</a>, <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CIHMJoEBv9D" target="_blank">Instagram</a>, and <a href="https://twitter.com/PaintZApp/status/1332393178314526721" target="_blank">Twitter</a>.
					</p>
				]]>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 11:00:00 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>PortalZ Developer Commentary</title>
			<link>https://zmyaro.com/blog/2020-11-12</link>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[
					<p>
						Last week, I released <a href="http://portalz.zmyaro.com/downloads/2020" target="_blank"><i>PortalZ: The 2020 Slice</i></a>.  It was interesting (if occasionally cringe-inducing) to look at how I had evolved as a level designer over the decade.  I would have liked to include a developer commentary mode like the original <i>Portal</i>, but in lieu of that, <a href="http://portalz.zmyaro.com/commentary" target="_blank">I added some written developer notes on the <i>PortalZ</i> website</a>.
					</p>
					<p style="font-style: italic;">
						Also posted to <a href="https://www.facebook.com/ZMYaro/posts/3578604185494101" target="_blank">Facebook</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/ZMYaro/status/1326911771949621248" target="_blank">Twitter</a>.
					</p>
				]]>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 10:00:00 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>PortalZ: The 2020 Slice</title>
			<link>https://zmyaro.com/blog/2020-11-05</link>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[
					<p>
						In the middle of summer lockdown, I had a sudden desire to revisit <i>PortalZ</i>.  I may not have had time to build every planned test chamber or correct every questionable 2009 design decision in the revamped chambers, but today, I am excited to release <a href="http://portalz.zmyaro.com/downloads/2020" target="_blank"><strong><em>PortalZ: The 2020 Slice</em></strong></a>, a pack of 14 test chambers for <i>Portal 1</i>!  Please feel free to give it a shot, share if you like it, and let me know what you think!
					</p>
					<p style="font-style: italic;">
						Also posted to <a href="https://www.facebook.com/ZMYaro/posts/3559242347430285" target="_blank">Facebook</a>, <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CHOXT2QLkBQ" target="_blank">Instagram</a>, and <a href="https://twitter.com/ZMYaro/status/1324429166348029955" target="_blank">Twitter</a>.
					</p>
				]]>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 5 Nov 2020 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Auto Theme Browser Extensions</title>
			<link>https://zmyaro.com/extensions/autotheme</link>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[
					<p>
						Some web apps allow you to set an app-specific dark/light theme preference, but have no option to match your system default.  <a href="https://zmyaro.com/extensions/autotheme" target="_blank">These extensions</a> enable that option for some popular web applications (currently Discord and Facebook).
					</p>
				]]>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 02:00:00 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Blocks</title>
			<link>https://zmyaro.com/games/blocks</link>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[
					<p>
						<a href="https://zmyaro.com/games/blocks" target="_blank" style="font-style: italic;">Blocks</a> is a game about intersectional identity I developed last weekend at the Possom House's Chill Jam 2.
					</p>
				]]>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 03:00:00 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Dessert Projects Section Added</title>
			<link>https://zmyaro.com/desserts</link>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[
					<p>
						As desserts go, I am not the biggest fan of cake, so I have kind of turned it into a tradition that every year for my birthday, I make myself a dessert project that mashes up multiple non-cake desserts.
					</p>
					<p>
						When I was really little, my mother was very kindly willing to make us whatever birthday cake we requested, but when I started requesting various non-cake things, it gradually evolved into the “if you want something done your way, do it yourself” take-over-the-kitchen-for-the-week monstrosity that it is today.
					</p>
					<p>
						There are not really any rules, but I generally try to incorporate one thing each year I had never made before or is somehow experimental, I try to make everything but the serving dish entirely edible, and I try not to use much food coloring—at most, I use a little to enhance a color that is already there. (The one place I cheat on that “rule” is if I am using something that has already been artificially colored, like Jell-O.)
					</p>
					<p>
						Also, yes, making any of these produces a good bit of extra food not pictured, but definitely shared with the people who partake in the pretty part of the “cake”.
					</p>
					<p style="font-style: italic;">
						This section for <a href="https://zmyaro.com/desserts" target="_blank">my dessert projects</a> has been added under my shenanigans, including <a href="https://zmyaro.com/desserts/2020" target="_blank">my newest one from last month</a>.
					</p>
				]]>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 8 Jul 2020 22:00:00 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Why Xe/Xem?</title>
			<link>https://zmyaro.com/blog/2020-07-01</link>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[
					<table>
						<tr>
							<th colspan="3">Pronouns</th>
							<th title="a.k.a. Subjective">Nomnative</th>
							<th><abbr title="Dependent">D.</abbr> Posessive</th>
							<th>Objective</th>
							<th><abbr title="Independent">I.</abbr> Posessive</th>
							<th>Reflexive</th>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<th rowspan="2">First<br />Person</th>
							<th colspan="2">Singular</th>
							<td>I</td>
							<td>my</td>
							<td>me</td>
							<td>mine</td>
							<td>myself</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<th colspan="2">Plural</th>
							<td>we</td>
							<td>our</td>
							<td>us</td>
							<td>ours</td>
							<td>ourselves</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<th rowspan="2">Second<br />Person</th>
							<th colspan="2">Singular</th>
							<td rowspan="2">you</td>
							<td rowspan="2">your</td>
							<td rowspan="2">you</td>
							<td rowspan="2">yours</td>
							<td>yourself</th>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<th colspan="2">Plural</th>
							<td>yourselves</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<th rowspan="6">Third<br />Person</th>
							<th rowspan="5">Singular</th>
							<th>Inanimate</th>
							<td>it</td>
							<td>its</td>
							<td>it</td>
							<td>its</td>
							<td>itself</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<th>Feminine</th>
							<td>she</td>
							<td>her</td>
							<td>her</td>
							<td>hers</td>
							<td>herself</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<th>Masculine</th>
							<td>he</td>
							<td>his</td>
							<td>him</td>
							<td>his</td>
							<td>himself</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<th rowspan="2">Neutral</th>
							<td>xe</td>
							<td>xer</td>
							<td>xem</td>
							<td>xers</td>
							<td>xemself</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td rowspan="2">they</td>
							<td rowspan="2">their</td>
							<td rowspan="2">them</td>
							<td rowspan="2">theirs</td>
							<td>themself</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<th colspan="2">Plural</th>
							<td>themselves</td>
						</tr>
					</table>
					
					<h2>Why a non-gender-coded third-person pronoun?</h2>
					<p>
						Myriad people benefit from the availability of non-gender-coded personal pronouns.  Obviously such terms are necessary for cases in which a person's gender is not known.  But normalizing the regular use of non-gender-coded pronouns are also useful in cases in which people might discriminate or make assumptions based on gender.  And of course, the community that has brought the most attention to the matter in recent years has been the nonbinary and genderqueer community—people who do not necessarily identify with female-coded pronouns like “she” or male-coded pronouns like “he”.
					</p>
					
					<h2>So no singular “they”?</h2>
					<p>
						Read the rest of this for how I ended up at “xe”, but let me say up front: Nothing in this post is permission to call people who prefer “they” by anything but their preferred pronouns.
					</p>
					<p>
						Having gotten that out of the way, it is true we could just live with “they” as both singular and plural—we already do that in second-person with “you” (though if I were not a few centuries late to the debate, I might also argue against the loss of separate singular and plural second-person pronouns 😛).  However, while not absolutely vital, it is very convenient, in relevant situations to be able to specify whether you mean an individual or a group.  That is why explicitly plural terms like “yous” and “y'all” have started catching on in second-person.  For a simple example, with “xe” as singular and “they” as plural, the difference is clear between, “I watched Tay's team; I thought xe played well,” and, “I watched Tay's team; I thought they played well.”
					</p>
					<p>
						There is the bonus of it being more straightforward for people learning English—it is extremely common, in second-person, for people to say “you is” because it makes more sense to use the singular verb when referring to a single person, even if it is officially incorrect.  Using an explicitly singular pronoun avoids that confusion as well.
					</p>
					
					<h2>How I got here</h2>
					<p>
						My path here arguably started in the 2006-2007 school year, when my English teacher corrected something I had written, in which I had used “they” to refer to a singular person of unknown gender, noting I should use “he or she” instead.  At the time, I thought “they” was exclusively plural, so her note seemed a valid correction according to the current rules of English grammar.  But while I used it, “he or she” always seemed cumbersome, and I wanted a term that could function like “they”, but specifically singular, and none existed.
					</p>
					<p>
						After a few years, I reached out to a transgender friend who had mentioned non-gender-specific third-person singular pronouns before, and learned a bit more about the non-standardized ones in use, such as xir, hir, and zir.
					</p>
					<p>
						I continued to keep the matter in the back of my mind, but no proposed non-gender-coded third-person singular personal pronoun was standardized.  Eventually around 2016-2017, I realized it had been a decade, and I decided to pick one.
					</p>
					
					<h2>The contenders</h2>
					<p>
						Many have been put forth, but some notable ones include “e”, “hir”, “ne”, “s/he”,“xe”, and “ze”.
					</p>
					<p>
						I was not terribly fond of “hir” and “s/he” because they were kind of implicitly combinations of “he” and “she”, which seemed less useful for people who identified outside the gender binary.
					</p>
					<p>
						Using “e”/“em” made a lot of sense, but had the issue that some accents pronounce leading “h”s silently (like most Americans do with “hour” or “herb”), so “e” would parse as “he” to them.  (That said, I would still be a big supporter of “e”/“em” if it caught on.)
					</p>
					<p>
						I recognize at this point it becomes even more subjective, but I preferred ones like “ne”, “xe”, and “ze” over ones like “xir” and “zir” because they are the easiest for people to swap in place of “he” or “she”—we already have people complaining saying, “No person is an island,” is somehow vastly inferior to, “No man...” so at least this way, “Let xe who is without sin...” reduces that as much as possible.
					</p>
					<p>
						So down to just ones like “ne”, “xe”, and “ze”.
					</p>
					
					<h2>Why xe?</h2>
					<p>
						Ultimately, it was subjective, but there were some things it aligned well with that led me to prefer it over the other 2:
					</p>
					<ul>
						<li>
							The pronunciation being phonetically similar to the “th” sound in “they”/“them”/“their”/“theirs”, making it more familiar to people already using those words (though that is also true of “ze”)
						</li>
						<li>
							𝒙 being commonly used in math to represent an unknown value (though that is also true of “ne” with 𝒏)
						</li>
						<li>
							Mx. being adopted as a gender-neutral alternative to Mr. and Ms.
						</li>
						<li>
							The Japanese 「Xジェンダー」 (“X-gender”) being roughly the equivalent of “genderqueer” (or anyone not expressly female or male)
						</li>
						<li>
							The Spanish -x suffix (as in “Latinx”) catching on as a neutral alternative to the gendered -a and -o (as in “Latina” and “Latino”)
						</li>
					</ul>
					<p>
						Thus, “xe”/“xem”/“xer”/“xers”.
					</p>
					
					<h2>How do I say/use it?</h2>
					<p>
						“Xe” is pronounced “zee” (like the first syllable of “xenolinguistics”).
						<br />
						“Xem” ⇒ “zem” or “zəm” (rhymes with “them”).
						<br />
						“Xer” ⇒ “zer” or “zər” (can rhyme with “her” or “their”).
					</p>
					<p>
						“He ate his sandwich by himself.  Someone asked him if it was his sandwich, and he confirmed it was his.”
						<br />
						“She ate her sandwich by herself.  Someone asked her if it was her sandwich, and she confirmed it was hers.”
						<br />
						“Xe ate xer sandwich by xemself.  Someone asked xem if it was xer sandwich, and xe confirmed it was xers.”
						<br />
						“They ate their sandwiches by themselves.  Someone asked them if they were their sandwiches, and they confirmed they were theirs.”
					</p>
					
					<h2>Additional notes:</h2>
					<ul>
						<li>
							Some people use the spelling “xir” or “xyr” instead of “xer”.  As far as I know, the reason usually just comes down to the spelling you were introduced to first, but I also, just personally, feel as though “xer” fits in better with the already-standardized third-person pronouns.
						</li>
						<li>
							Early on, I referred to “he” and “she” as “male-coded” and “female-coded”, respectively, because that is how they are generally viewed, but it is worth noting not <em>everyone</em> who uses those pronouns identifies as “male” or “female”, so it is still good to confirm rather than assuming.
						</li>
						<li>
							Finally, I feel as though I need to reiterate: this post is not to be used as justification for you to disregard anyone's preferred pronouns.
						</li>
					</ul>
				]]>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Voice Actions for Chrome v4.6</title>
			<link>https://zmyaro.com/extensions/voiceactions</link>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[
					<p>
						<a href="https://zmyaro.com/extensions/voiceactions" target="_blank">Voice Actions for Chrome</a> v4.6 update adds a variety of improvements, most notably a full Material Design refresh and support for dark theme.  The full changelog includes:
					</p>
					<ul>
						<li>Adds warning when no microphone is detected</li>
						<li>Adds warning when microphone access has been denied</li>
						<li>Adds link to Chrome permission settings page from permission prompt page and from other pages when microphone access has been denied</li>
						<li>Keyboard shortcut to activate Voice Actions is set to Alt+V by default</li>
						<li>Keyboard shortcut is now also mentioned in extension options</li>
						<li>Adds new search engine options</li>
						<li>Also deprecates some that have gone defunct</li>
						<li>Also updates some that have changed URLs</li>
						<li>Also renames some that have changed names</li>
						<li>Changes default music search app to Spotify (as much as I still like Google Music)</li>
						<li>Updates extension pages to follow system dark theme preference</li>
						<li>Updates pop-up to better follow Material Design guidelines</li>
						<li>Updates icons to new Material Design ones</li>
						<li>Updates icons to SVGs</li>
						<li>Adds embedded options page (opens on chrome://extensions instead of its own tab)</li>
						<li>Adds links to Voice Actions Facebook and Twitter pages, removes Google+ (R.I.P. ☹)</li>
						<li>Fixes pop-up load indicator flickering</li>
					</ul>
				]]>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2020 02:00:00 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Why Pride?</title>
			<link>https://zmyaro.com/blog/2019-07-19</link>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[
					<p>
						Roc Pride Festival is tomorrow!  I figured I would briefly mention why I care about Pride stuff.  I spent several years not wanting being queer to be a major part of my identity (“Cishet people do not need to ‘come out’ or remind people who they are, so why should I?”), and in many ways, that is still my stance, but even from there, I have started being more “aggressively” or “overtly” queer—having a rainbow flag up, wearing more Pride flag colors, etc.  To me, that accomplishes a few important things: 1) it tells other queer people they are not alone, 2) it tells other queer people they can safely be their queer selves around me, and 3) it prevents bigots who want to ignore/erase the existence of queer people from doing so.  Pride is that sentiment on steroids.  It shows queer people just how many other queer people live in their town (and beyond), it gives them a much larger space in which to safely be their queer selves, and it sends a massive message to everyone in power who wants to erase us that we do and will continue to exist and persist.
					</p>
					<br />
					<p style="font-style: italic;">
						Cross-posted to <a href="https://www.facebook.com/ZMYaro/posts/2417223771632154" target="_blank">Facebook</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/ZMYaro/status/1152290297252065282" target="_blank">Twitter</a>.
					</p>
				]]>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 14:30:00 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Just Change Your Mind</title>
			<link>https://zmyaro.com/music/justchangeyourmind</link>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[
					<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Kr8ODkS2jBI" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen style="margin: auto; max-width: 100%;"></iframe>
					<p>
						This idea came to me while I was watching the <i>Steven Universe</i> S5 finale, and no one has done it yet, so I made it.  Happy Pride month 2019!
					</p>
					<p>
						Video: Steven Universe S5E32 &ldquo;Change Your Mind, Part 4&rdquo;, directed by Joe Johnston, Kat Morris, and Liz Artinian
						<br />
						Music: &ldquo;Raise You Up / Just Be&rdquo; from Kinky Boots, music and lyrics by Cyndi Lauper
						<br />
						Editing: Zachary Yaro
						<br />
						Created with Adobe Premiere CS6
					</p>
					<p>
						This is a fan-made (not for profit) video, and the materials in this video are not related in any way to myself or each other outside of it.  Please support the original works.
					</p>
					<p style="font-style: italic;">
						Cross-posted to <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Kr8ODkS2jBI" target="_blank">YouTube</a>,
						<a href="https://www.facebook.com/ZMYaro/videos/2359037960784069" target="_blank">Facebook</a>,
						<a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/ByyOapigdzu" target="_blank">Instagram</a>, and
						<a href="https://twitter.com/ZMYaro/status/1140366675654713352" target="_blank">Twitter</a>.
					</p>
				]]>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2019 16:15:00 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Rant: Emoji</title>
			<link>https://zmyaro.com/blog/2016-05-13</link>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[
					<p>
						You may have heard about <a href="http://www.unicode.org/L2/L2016/16160-emoji-professions.pdf" target="_blank">a recent proposal to include gendered profession emoji</a>.  If you have not, the basic idea is to allow the woman (U+1F469) and man (U+1F468) emoji to be combined with others to represent various professions.  While I do not have a reason to oppose profession emoji (other than the common complaint about there being too many emoji), I do oppose pushing these emoji in the name of diversity and representation.
					</p>
					<figure data-side="right">
						<img src="https://zmyaro.com/blog/2016-05-13/emoji_skin_tone.png" alt="Unicode 8.0 skin tone modifiers" style="width: 100%; max-width: 300px;" />
						<figcaption>Unicode 8.0 skin tone modifiers (from <a href="http://www.macrumors.com/2014/11/04/emoji-diversity-skin-tone-modifier" target="_blank">Mac Rumors</a>)</figcaption>
					</figure>
					<p>
						Issues of representation and diversity in emoji were in the news not that long ago when <a href="http://blog.unicode.org/2015/06/announcing-unicode-standard-version-80.html" target="_blank">Unicode 8.0</a> introduced skin tone modifiers.  Until Apple's color emoji gained popularity, most computers rendered emoji like any other text&mdash;in the text's font color.  The font color could, of course, be set by whatever software was rendering the text.  Want to honor the Wicked Witch of the West?  Set the font color to green and give her a thumbs up (U+1F44D).  After all, the percent sign (U+0025) does not tell you what color it should be; why should any other character?
					</p>
					<p>
						Color emoji took considerable control away from content creators.  Suddenly, if you wanted to use the &ldquo;back with leftwards arrow above&rdquo; (U+1F519) emoji, you were out of luck on the platforms on which it always rendered in blue unless that fit with your app's color scheme.  For the first time, a huge number of characters had the ability to tell font rendering programs what color they wanted to be, and designers and content creators had no say in the matter.
					</p>
					<p>
						Even with the introduction of various color emoji sets (or &ldquo;smilies&rdquo;, as we used to call them in the U.S.), emoji remained gender- and racially-neutral.  The yellow smiley face used to be virtually universally recognized as representing a happy human face without any indicators of gender, race, or any other physical traits&mdash;it remained as unbiased as the classic &ldquo;:)&rdquo;.  It was only when Apple released emoji with caucasian skin tones that people took issue.  To be perfectly clear, I think people were absolutely right to oppose Apple's change&mdash;by explicitly representing one racial group, Apple had implicitly excluded all others.  I do, however take issue with the Unicode consortium's solution.
					</p>
					<p>
						The introduction of skin tone modifiers suddenly made font color selection a choice that could be made by the typeface, and while emoji were no longer limited to a single skin tone, they <em>were</em> still limited to six.  Once again, by including selected groups instead of opening emoji to the full range of possible font colors, every other group had been implicitly excluded.
					</p>
					<figure data-side="right">
						<img src="https://zmyaro.com/blog/2016-05-13/police_emoji.png" alt="Google police officer emoji" style="max-width: 120px;" />
						<figcaption style="max-width: 192px;">Google's gender-neutral police officer emoji</figcaption>
					</figure>
					<p>
						This brings me to this newest proposal.  In the past, profession emoji, such as the police officer (U+1F46E) have not had specified genders, and while some fonts contanied gendered versions of the character, others, such as Google, kept them as androgynous as the first smilies, and that decision is important.  As I stated before, as soon as you modify emoji to explicitly represent specific groups, you implicitly exclude all others.  By gendering profession emoji, you implicitly exclude non-binary individuals.  Additionally, you exclude anyone whose definition of his/her own masculinity or femininity does not match Google's representation.  These modifiers do not include long-haired males, short-haired females, people who express gender identity with facial hair, and, obviously, anyone without brown hair.
					</p>
					<p>
						Instead of continuing to add and add until emoji capture every person's unique traits, consider moving emoji back toward the more abstract representations they once were, and stop letting the text tell the application how it should look.  The more emoji cease to be neutral and try to represent specific traits, the more it becomes apparent just how many more unique traits exist in humanity than can possibly be represented, and the more groups get implicitly excluded.
					</p>
				]]>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 00 Jan 2013 00:00:00 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Review: Her</title>
			<link>https://zmyaro.com/blog/2014-03-17</link>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[
					<p>
						I finally watched <i>Her</i> today.  As someone with interests in both AI development and philosophy, I thought it was quite excellent.  I was not a fan of the musical choices, but the writing and directing made the characters feel very real, and the movie deserves major kudos for that.  I thought the ending felt a bit cop-out-y, but I was not any more sure of where the story was going to go than the writers seemed to be.
					</p>
					<h3>Story: 6/7</h3>
					<p>
						The characters were very well-written.  My only complaint was the rather anticlimactic ending.  It fit the movie, but for lack of a better way to describe it, it felt as though the writers just had an ending happen out of nowhere because the movie needed to end.
					</p>
					<h3>Visuals/cinematography: 5/7</h3>
					<p>
						Not bad, but nothing exceptional.
					</p>
					<h3>Music/sound: 3/7</h3>
					<p>
						Some of the music fit the movie, but some of it just started to annoy me.  It felt as though it got in the way of what was happening rather than enhancing the moment as it should have.  Kudos, though, to whoever was in charge of the various sound effects for different OSes.
					</p>
					<h3>Overall: 6/7</h3>
					<p>
						This movie delivered on everything I hoped it would (and a few things I hoped to be wrong about).  It was an excellent story about human interaction, human-computer interaction, and humans and AIs handling existential crises.  A few things here and there felt ever so slightly off, but I still highly recommend this movie.
					</p>
				]]>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2014 01:00:00 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Rant: Google, Stop Killing Things - Part 4: I Will Not Use Keep</title>
			<link>https://zmyaro.com/blog/2013-03-21</link>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[
					<p>
						As you may have heard, <a href="https://drive.google.com/keep" target="_blank">Google Keep</a> is live (for real this time).  I, for one, will not be switching to it.  The reason is simple.  As Google <a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2011/09/fall-spring-clean.html" target="_blank">has</a> <a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2011/10/fall-sweep.html" target="_blank">shown</a> <a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2011/11/more-spring-cleaning-out-of-season.html" target="_blank">us</a> <a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2012/04/spring-cleaning-in-spring.html" targe="_blank">with</a> <a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2012/07/spring-cleaning-in-summer.html" target="_blank">its</a> &ldquo;<a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2012/09/more-spring-cleaning.html" target="_blank">spring</a> <a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2012/12/winter-cleaning.html" target="_blank">cleaning</a>&rdquo; <a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2013/03/a-second-spring-of-cleaning.html" target="_blank">events</a> (and most notably, for me, with the death of Google Reader), it is a big company that does a lot of things, and it does not always want to keep doing all those things.  I do not see Keep as being hugely beneficial to Google as a business, so I could easily see it getting killed in a year or two.  On top of that, Google Killed its last note-taking product, Google Notebook, in <a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2011/09/fall-spring-clean.html" target="_blank">a previous &ldquo;spring cleaning&rdquo;</a>
					</p>
					<p>
						My preferred notes app right now is <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.akproduction.notepad" target="_blank">AK Notepad</a>, a lightweight version of <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.threebanana.notes" target="_blank">Catch Notes</a> (both are made by the same company).  The reason I intend to stay with AK/Catch is the same reason <a href="http://evernote.com" target="_blank">Evernote</a> users should stick with Evernote: <strong>note taking apps are what these companies do</strong>.  A company like Catch or Evernote is not going to kill its note taking app during &ldquo;spring cleaning&rdquo; because then <strong>the company would not exist</strong>.
					</p>
					<br />
					<p>
						On a side note (no pun intended), this could, arguably, be used as a reason to pick Facebook over Google+: Google+ is part of a social <em>strategy</em> for Google, but social <em>is</em> Facebook.  Without a social network, Google would control a bit less of the Internet than it does.  Without a social network, Facebook <strong>would not exist</strong>.
					</p>
					<br />
					<p>
						<strong>Edit (2013-07-30):</strong> Apparently I underestimated Catch's desire to exist.  Catch has announced it will soon be killing Catch Notes “to take the company in a different direction.”  Evernote's UX is bad enough that I am willing to give Google Keep a shot (at least until a decent competitor comes along).
					</p>
					<br />
					<p style="font-style: italic;">
						Feel free to comment <a href="https://plus.google.com/114745581771396366390/posts/Yamp4iispqW" target="_blank">on Google+</a>
					</p>
				]]>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2013 15:00:00 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Rant: Google, Stop Killing Things - Part 3: What Will Be Next To Go?</title>
			<link>https://zmyaro.com/blog/2013-03-18</link>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[
					<p>
						Since it is apparent Google's &ldquo;spring cleaning&rdquo; was not a one-time thing, I am starting to wonder what other Google products may be on the chopping block soon.  Here are some thoughts.
					</p>
					<h4><a href="http://feedburner.google.com" target="_blank">FeedBurner</a></h4>
					<p>
						The death of Google Reader AND iGoogle basically removes Google from the RSS game on the feed <em>reading</em> side, but FeedBurner is still around serving feeds.  Will Google choose to close down FeedBurner and abandon RSS completely, or do enough sites use FeedBurner to make it worth keeping around?
					</p>
					<h4><a href="https://mail.google.com/tasks/canvas" target="_blank">Google Tasks</a></h4>
					<p>
						Google Tasks is a fantastic product.  It is conveniently built into Gmail and Google Calendar, and it has a lot of very nice mobile apps (even if none are from Google).  On the other hand, there has been zero activity on the product in quite a while&mdash;often a sign that Google is preparing to kill it.  In addition, the recently leaked Google Keep includes checklist functionality, which may replace Google Tasks.  Overall, though, I get the impression that Google Tasks is a product a lot of people use on a day-to-day basis, but not enough for it to influence Google.
					</p>
					<h4><a href="https://groups.google.com" target="_blank">Google Groups</a></h4>
					<p>
						I actually thought Google Groups was close to death a couple times in the past.  The recent redesigns have breathed some new life into it, but it still does not seem to be most people's go-to mailing list or forum solution outside of Google.  On top of that, Google seems to be pushing Google+Communities as its preferred way for users to communicate within a group.
					</p>
					<h4><a href="http://google.com/webfonts" target="_blank">Google Web Fonts</a></h4>
					<p>
						This is mostly on the grounds that Google Web Fonts still has its pre-Google+ UI, whereas nearly every surviving product that is not near death has seen a redesign.  It could be that Google recognizes that Web Fonts has a perfectly usable UI...or it could be that Google does not intend to continue working on its Web Fonts site.
					</p>
					<h4><a href="http://talk.google.com" target="_blank">Google Talk</a> (as we know it)</h4>
					<p>
						Let me be clear: I am not predicting the death of Google Talk.  What I AM saying is I could see Google moving to a new instant messaging service that is not based on standards like XMPP.  Rumors of a new messaging service codenamed &ldquo;Babble&rdquo; have begun to surface, and it is likely we will see the future of Google chat services at I/O in May.
					</p>
					<p>
						In addition, Google Talk voice and video chat are likely to be shut down as they get replaced by Google+Hangouts.  When they work, I actually prefer Google Talk video chats over Hangouts&mdash;particularly on mobile where the app requires less resources&mdash;but Hangouts are definitely more reliable, and they are clearly where Google is focusing its engineering efforts.
					</p>
					<br />
					<p style="font-style: italic;">
						Feel free to comment <a href="https://plus.google.com/114745581771396366390/posts/XBwMok1CzAV" target="_blank">on Google+</a>
					</p>
				]]>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 19:00:00 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>Rant: Google, Stop Killing Things - Part 2: Google Buzz</title>
			<link>https://zmyaro.com/blog/2013-03-15</link>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[
					<p>
						A surprisingly large number of my friends in high school used Google Buzz.  It had a rocky start, but once we got used to it we realized it was a much more convenient and versatile social platform than Facebook.  Even just the fact that you could attach multiple photos from a given link was a great improvement.  Not to mention the convenience of having it integrated right into Gmail.  Fast forward to the end of 2011.  Google+ was still in an invite-only adults-only test phase, but Google decided that was a good time to kill Buzz.  No migrating posts from Buzz to G+; no giving loyal Buzz users access to G+; the Buzz tab in Gmail just...disappeared.  Why could Buzz not cleanly merge into G+?  The posts looked identical on my profile.  A Buzz &ldquo;Like&rdquo; is basically the equivalent of a +1.  Given that someone was able to write a program that used Buzz and Facebook's APIs to make Facebook comments appear on Buzz and Buzz comments appear on Facebook, I am certain <em>someone</em> in Google could have been smart enough to figure out how to import Buzz posts into G+.
					</p>
					<p>
						But no, one day we woke up and Buzz was just gone.  And what did my Buzz loving friends realize?  Why, they realized that from before Buzz was given to them and after it was taken away, Facebook had reliably stuck around.  It is no wonder I cannot get those friends to leave FB for G+.  Heck, with all the good Google products that get killed, I am wondering if I should start running my own e-mail server in case they announce Gmail going down.  After all, there are even more alternatives for Gmail users than for Wave and Reader users combined!
					</p>
					<br />
					<p style="font-style: italic;">
						Feel free to comment <a href="https://plus.google.com/114745581771396366390/posts/EDSQ3GxgGKg" target="_blank">on Google+</a>
					</p>
				]]>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 15:00:00 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Rant: Google, Stop Killing Things - Part 1: iGoogle and Google Reader</title>
			<link>https://zmyaro.com/blog/2013-03-14</link>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[
					<p>
						I am going to leave Google Wave out of this.  Wave was not incredibly popular or successful.  I will accept that for the duration of this rant series.
					</p>
					<p>
						What about the other products Google is killing?  They are dying at different speeds, but many of Google's products&mdash;including a lot that brought me to Google in the first place&mdash;are being killed.
					</p>
					<p>
						This is, of course, prompted by the announcement that Google Reader would be going down.  Let me talk for a moment about my experience with RSS aggregators.  I was not a huge fan of the ones built into browsers.  I think IE8's was the best, and even that was not so great.  Then I found iGoogle.  Keep in mind this is before I was a Gmail user and way before I was a Google Docs user.  Anyway, following my discovery of iGoogle, it remained my homepage on every computer I used for a good 5-7 years.  Actually, it is technically <em>still</em> my homepage; I just stopped visiting it regularly because Chrome is set to &ldquo;Continue where I left off.&rdquo;  My mom also still has iGoogle as her home page and it will remain there until Google shuts it down <em>because there is no good alternative.</em>  So iGoogle was my first online RSS aggregator.  It conveniently let me display any feed on my home page as a widget.  Eventually, I collected too many feeds for that to be convenient, so I poked around and discovered Google had an even better tool for the job than iGoogle: Google Reader.  You know what made Google Reader fantastic?  It WORKED.  Gmail, Google Calendar, Google Docs, all the big name Google products saw redesign after redesign.  Google Reader just WORKED.  The only time Google Reader got a redesign was when the execs behind Google+ MADE THEM do a redesign.  And now that that is over, Google Reader is solid once again.  In fact, if Google just let Reader sit as is without any developers working on it IT WOULD PROBABLY HAVE LESS DOWNTIME THAN GMAIL AND MORE ACTIVE USERS THAN GOOGLE+.
					</p>
					<br />
					<p style="font-style: italic;">
						Feel free to comment <a href="https://plus.google.com/114745581771396366390/posts/5VAuNjgcBFV" target="_blank">on Google+</a>
					</p>
				]]>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2013 15:00:00 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Rant: Google Is The New Microsoft</title>
			<link>https://zmyaro.com/blog/2013-03-13</link>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[
					<p>
						Google used to care so much about standards and openness.  They had the most standards-compliant browser, an RSS/Atom feed aggregator, and search results from social circles meant Buzz, Twitter, Flickr, and anyone else willing to let Google index its data.
					</p>
					<p>
						Now Google is basically at the top—or close enough that it feels like it is.  Suddenly they have lost interest in openness and standards.  Now -webkit- prefixes and chrome.* APIs are going to make Chrome the new IE.  Google's focus has shifted from the open web to the Chrome web.  Google+ is replacing Google's old work at aggregating social data from a variety of networks.  In Buzz and Reader, users could pull in tweets, Flickr uploads, blog posts, RSS feeds, FriendFeed content, and more.  Google+ keeps everything tightly under Google's control.
					</p>
					<p>
						Where is this going to go next?  I could definitely see Google abandoning XMPP Google Talk for some non-standards-based expansion of Google+ Messenger.  One thing is for sure, the Google that built its image as a company that put the interests of the Internet as a whole before its own interests is gone.  Google is very quickly ceasing to be special and becoming yet another rich company.
					</p>
					<p>
						Long story short, Google was calling for open standards when others were in charge.  Now it is on top, it is happy to take advantage of that, and its products are so nice that we are not going to stop them.  At least I am not.  I like Gmail too much.
					</p>
					<p>
						And, oddly enough, it is now <em>Microsoft</em> calling for open standards.  Funny how these things go...
					</p>
					<br />
					<p style="font-style: italic;">
						Feel free to comment <a href="https://plus.google.com/114745581771396366390/posts/EFWA3jJgkMC" target="_blank">on Google+</a>
					</p>
				]]>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2013 19:00:00 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>AndRant: Not Everywhere I Stop Is A Business</title>
			<link>https://zmyaro.com/blog/2013-02-26</link>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[
					<p>
						When I spend a lot of time at someone's house Google Latitude Location History always thinks I was at the nearest business instead.  You have my contact list, Google!  Why would you think I was at a business I have never heard of instead of, for instance, my girlfriend's house, which I visit very frequently and is closer to my GPS- and wi-fi-based locations than the nearby business suggestions??  Or why not look at my Navigation history, which is saved IN THE SAME APP and maybe conclude that if my GPS location is close enough to it, the address I entered there was probably where I went?!
					</p>
					<aside>
						<img src="https://zmyaro.com/blog/2013-02-26/location_history1.png" />
						<img src="https://zmyaro.com/blog/2013-02-26/location_history2.png" />
					</aside>
					<p>
						Feel free to comment <a href="https://plus.google.com/114745581771396366390/posts/3PsyE7rPsJx" target="_blank">on Google+</a>.
					</p>
				]]>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2013 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Concerns Regarding “The Snowmen”</title>
			<link>http://zmyaro.com/blog/post.html#2012-12-10</link>
			<description>
				<p>
					I am concerned about the <i>Doctor Who</i> Christmas special, “The Snowmen.”  I am afraid it will suffer from the same problems as “The Wedding Of River Song”<small> (s6ep13)</small>.  That is, it will try to cram too much into a single one-part episode and end up feeling rushed or incomplete.
				</p>
				<p>
					Consider the number of things this episode is going to have happen (in no particular order):
				</p>
				<ul>
					<li>The effect the loss of the Ponds has had on The Doctor needs to be shown</li>
					<li>The Doctor will be convinced to come out of retirement.</li>
					<li>The TARDIS will regenerate.</li>
					<li>The new companion, Clara, will be introduced.</li>
					<li>The characters Madame Vastra, Jenny, and Strax will be fleshed out more than in “A Good Man Goes To War”<small> (s6ep7)</small>.</li>
					<li>The new villain, Doctor Simeon, will be introduced.</li>
				</ul>
				<p>
					Okay, so introducing a one-episode villain is not a big deal, but the TARDIS regenerating and the introduction of Clara are kind of big.  Also, time needs to be dedicated to showing The Doctor's state after losing the ponds.  Episodes like “A Town Called Mercy”<small> (s7ep3)</small> were intended to show how The Doctor's companions were part of his moral compass.  “The Snowmen” needs to show how The Doctor has changed without them.
				</p>
				<p>
					Comments?  Discuss on the <a href="https://plus.google.com/114745581771396366390/posts/PsDc8N2KgU3" target="_blank">Google+ thread</a>.
				</p>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2012 23:59:59 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Rant: I Want You To Take My Money, But You Want Me To Want To Keep It (Part 1: Nintendo)</title>
			<link>http://zmyaro.com/blog/post.html#2012-11-23</link>
			<description>
				<p>
					Thanksgiving is over, so the time for holiday shopping has officially begun.  This has, of course, made me think about what sort of things <i>I</i> want this year.  However, thinking through the companies whose products I normally drool over, I am realizing they must want me to keep my money this year.
				</p>
				<p>
					First off, Nintendo.  Anyone who knows me probably knows I am quite a Nintendo fanboy, and have been for years.  In 2006, I drooled over the Wii and drove from store to store for months until I finally got one.  When I heard Nintendo was working on a successor to the Wii, I was excited...until I saw what it was.  The Wii was revolutionary, but the Wii U seems to fall short in every possible respect.  And now I shall complain about them in no particular order.
				</p>
				<p>
					My first complaint is that, Nintendo has been bragging about the Wii U's graphics...and ignoring the fact that the Xbox 360 was capable of comparable graphics <i>before the Wii came out</i>!  Nintendo has never been known for being the best at graphics or processing power, but it also never tried to brag when it knew it was behind.  Now it is bragging that its next-gen console has current-gen graphics.
				</p>
				<p>
					Next, Miiverse, Nintendo's new gaming-oriented social network, will probably fail about as badly as Apple's music-oriented social network, “Ping.”  At best, people might visit Miiverse occasionally with questions, but it is unlikely most users will check for Miiverse posts as frequently as Facebook, Google+, or Twitter.  Also, when did “Yeah” become a verb?
				</p>
				<p>
					Another complaint is the fact that the Wii Menu exists at all on the Wii U.  This is the same as one of my big complaints about Windows 8: If your new OS is so great, why is your old OS hacked onto it?  The Wii was able to play GameCube games pretty seamlessly.  Why is Wii U backward compatibility such a mess?
				</p>
				<p>
					Maybe it would help if Nintendo actually had some decent sort of account system to sync games from Wii's to Wii U's (and maybe DSi's to 3DSes).  I am a Club Nintendo member, and my Wii Shop Channel account is linked to my Club Nintendo membership.  Why not have Club Nintendo, Miiverse, my Nintendo eShop purchases, and maybe even all that friend code nonsense be synced with one central account?  How can Nintendo expect people to trust its online gaming, social networking, or digital download offerings if it gives no evidence it cares about having a reliable backend.  I trust that when I buy a game from the Google Play Store or the Windows Store, that purchase is saved to my Google/Microsoft account and can be accessed from any Android/Windows 8 device I sign into, should the download fail or my original device break.  When I buy a game from the Wii Shop Channel/Nintendo eShop, I trust that that game will be on that console at that time and nothing more.  If anything happens to my Wii, I have no idea if I will get that game back.  Similarly, if I want to play a game online from an Xbox or Windows 8 device, I just need to exchange gamer tags, which are, again, linked to Microsoft accounts.  If my Wii breaks, I have to exchange Wii numbers and friend codes for every friend and every game.  I have no idea who thought that up, but he or she clearly does not understand UX.
				</p>
				<p style="font-size: smaller;">
					(I should mention, a lot of that is hypothetical.  I am not an Xbox or Windows 8 fan.  That said, the way those situations <i>would</i> play out is accurate.)
				</p>
				<p>
					One small penultimate complaint is about Nintendo TVii.  My main disappointment there, apart from the fact that the feature was not available at launch, is that the Wii U's only awesome feature is not even related to gaming.  In addition, the fact that it even lagged in the promo video greatly lowers my expectations.
				</p>
				<p>
					My last complaint is about the Wii U GamePad.  I will admit I found the idea of bringing the touch screen idea from the DS to console gaming kind of clever.  But, compared to something like Xbox SmartGlass, Nintendo's idea seems terrible.  Sure, there will likely be some awesome experiences that result from the combination of a controller and a touch screen, but there are so many situations where the GamePad will cause problems.
				</p>
				<p>
					Example #1: Someone makes a game that uses the GamePad for something.  Three of your friends come over to play multiplayer.  The Wii U only supports two GamePads at a time.  What do?
				</p>
				<p>
					Example #2: You are playing a game online using the Pro Controller.  You want to voice chat with the other players.  The headset must be plugged into the GamePad; not the Pro Controller or the Wii U console.  o_O
				</p>
				<p>
					Example #3: Every first-person shooter that could be made more awesome with the Wii Remote's precision will now be required to drop that in favor of some sort of touch screen gimmick.
				</p>
				<p>
					In addition, there is the issue of making every Wii U owner buy a Nintendo Wii U GamePad if he or she wants another.  Compare that to SmartGlass where just about any mobile device (my Galaxy Nexus, my dad's IdeaPad, my friend's Surface, my girlfriend's dad's iPad, etc.) can be that second screen.  Oh, and this second screen has multi-touch.  As one friend of mine likes to put it, “You are never finished buying a Nintendo product.”  This has never been more true than with the Wii U, which is technically not complete without four Wii Remotes, four Wii Nunchuks, a Wii Balance Board, two Wii U GamePads, and four Wii U Pro Controllers (plus, optionally, four Wii Classic Controllers or Classic Controller Pros).
				</p>
				<p>
					I feel like I probably will buy a Wii U at some point just to play <i>New Super Mario Bros. U</i>, <i>ZombiU</i>, and <i>Nintendoland</i>, but, at this point, the Wii U is nothing but a box of disappointments.  And a slate of disappointments.  And another controller.  And Wii Remotes.  And some other controllers.  All the controllers.
				</p>
				<p>
					(Also, yes, I realize I got off Wii U-specific complaints into general Nintendo complaints, but I suppose the complaints about Nintendo's online offerings also cover why I never bought a 3DS or DSi.)
				</p>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2012 02:40:00 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>“The Angels Take Manhattan” Predictions</title>
			<link>http://zmyaro.com/blog/post.html#2012-09-28</link>
			<description>
				<p>
					Tomorrow will be the Ponds' last episode.  I wanted to throw out some last-minute predictions.  First though, some things that have been confirmed:
				</p>
				<ul>
					<li>It will be set in Manhattan (duh).</li>
					<li>Amy will be trying to save Rory.</li>
					<li>Melody Pond/River Song will appear.</li>
					<li>The Weeping Angels will return to their old habit of sending people back in time (as in “Blink” (s3)) instead of breaking necks (as in “Time Of Angels” (s5)).</li>
					<li>They (presumably the Angels) are coming for Rory (according to The Doctor).</li>
					<li>One or more people will witness his/her/their own future(s).</li>
				</ul>
				<p>And now, my predictions:</p>
				<ul>
					<li>If The Statue Of Liberty is an Angel, I totally called it.</li>
					<li>The combination of Angels sending people back in time and Amy, Rory, and Melody being there makes me think they might reference one of the last couple times Melody was in New York (possibly when she was there with The Silence as a child - see “The Impossible Astronaut”/“Day Of The Moon” (s6)).</li>
					<li>“Time Of Angels” (s5) confirmed the Angels can “infect” people by looking people in their eyes.  I think this is going to happen to Rory.</li>
					<li>Amy is supposed to have a huge fear of the Weeping Angels (they were apparently her worst fear, according to “The God Complex” (s6)).  It is not usually referenced, but it may become important here.</li>
					<li>Rory always escapes death, so maybe he actually dies here.  Or maybe, because we would expect that to happen, Amy dies here.  Or maybe, since the first image for s6 set us up to expect that, Rory dies here.  Or maybe, since the trailer shows The Doctor telling Rory “they're coming for you,” they set us up to expect <i>Rory</i> to die, and <i>Amy</i> dies.  Or maybe they both get zapped back to 1969 and get to raise little Melody and live happily ever after apart from the whole stuck-back-in-time thing.  I do not know.</li>
				</ul>
				<p>
					Comments?  Discuss on the <a href="https://plus.google.com/114745581771396366390/posts/L582W9ggArH" target="_blank">Google+ thread</a>.
				</p>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2012 21:50:00 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Random Doctor Who Predictions</title>
			<link>http://zmyaro.com/blog/post.html#2012-09-13</link>
			<description>
				<h3>1:</h3>
				<p>
					It is not exactly normal for The Doctor to switch back and forth between traveling on his own and traveling with his primary companion(s), as he is with Amy and Rory in season 7 (though I agree it <i>is</i> justifiable in this case).  What if all or part of season 7's episodes and/or <i>Pond Life</i> take place in The Doctor's timeline after “Angels Take Manhattan”?  It would certainly explain The Doctor's sadness in the last episode of <i>Pond Life</i> if he were trying to have adventures with the Ponds while knowing what will happen to them.
				</p>
				<h3>2:</h3>
				<p>
					Another (incompatible) theory: The Ponds' departure is supposed to be final, but nothing stops him from visiting Amy and Rory earlier in their timelines (like he did Rose at the end of “The End Of Time”).  What if the Ponds' departure in “Angels Take Manhattan” involves letting one or both Ponds survive, but prevents The Doctor from seeing them again (like Donna)?
				</p>
				<p>
					Do you have comments on either of these theories?  <a href="https://plus.google.com/114745581771396366390/posts/1cnDBCGs1sJ" target="_blank">Share your comments on Google+</a>
				</p>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2012 22:50:00 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Responses To Asylum Of The Daleks</title>
			<link>http://zmyaro.com/blog/post.html#2012-09-02</link>
			<description>
				<p>
					Last year, after each episode of <i>Doctor Who</i>, I updated a wave with my latest comments and predictions.  That worked very well because wave was a great platform for letting me maintain that list <i>and</i> letting other people comment on what I said.  Since that is not really an option this year, I have decided to just put my comments in blog posts.  If you want to comment, you should do so on the Google+ where I link to the blog post (until I decide how I want to rewrite commenting into my blog, since Google broke my previous wave-based system).
				</p>
				<p>
					“Asylum Of The Daleks” was a great way to start the series...for the most part.  I will start with the things I did like, make a smooth-ish transition to my complaints, and end with my predictions.  Oh, and I will talk a bit about “Pond Life” (the prequel mini-series) as well.
				</p>
				<h2>SPOILERS FOLLOW.  YOU HAVE BEEN WARNED.</h2>
				<p>
					The episode starts off pretty well.  Seeing Skaro was kind of neat (despite potential continuity issues), and introducing a new type of Dalek-in-a-human was a surprising twist.  I enjoyed asylum itself largely because, having seen some old <i>Who</i>, I recognized some of the old Daleks.  I also liked how the episode made the Daleks seem like much more than mindless killing machines—both through the Daleks talking about having a concept of beauty, as well as things like Amy seeing other Daleks as regular people when viewing them from a Dalek's perspective.  Even though I predicted Oswin would be a Dalek from early on—though I was expecting another puppet, and I think the episode was written so I would expect that—I still really enjoyed not only the idea of a human in a Dalek shell, but also the ideas about what a person—or possibly any being—would perceive when put in a Dalek shell like that.  Finally, the ending.  I think a lot of fun things could result from this ending.  On one hand, the Daleks will no longer want to kill The Doctor, but, on the other hand, they no longer have the fear and respect(?) for him that they previously had.  Think about how many times The Doctor has stopped his enemies just with his reputation (e.g., “The Pandorica Opens,” (s5) “Silence In The Library” (s4)).
				</p>
				<p>
					The episode is not without its problems, however, and I do not mean Moffat trickiness (though there is that too).  I will start with “Pond Life.”  I liked the first four episodes of the mini-series.  Sure, they were short, but they were fun and silly.  The last episode turns sad out of nowhere.  I had no idea when this was taking place; initially I thought it was after “The Angels Take Manhattan” and The Doctor was trying to pretend Amy and Rory were still there but then it showed Amy kicking Rory out and I got really confused.  I tried to give the series the benefit of the doubt, though, and waited for “Asylum Of The Daleks.”  Unfortunately, it did not help.  If “Pond Life” were all supposed to be a direct prologue to s7ep1, it would have made sense to have all five episodes lead to the divorce, not have it just suddenly appear.  It got worse when they explained <i>why</i> they got divorced.  Given how Amy and Rory were portrayed in the past, they seem like a couple that could handle not being able to have more children (have they never heard of adoption?), not just jump to divorce.
				</p>
				<p>
					Finally, predictions.  I think the Amy/Rory situation is pretty much resolved because it was only supposed to be important for one scene.  What is not resolved, however, is Oswin.  While two actresses who played companions <i>did</i> show up in episodes as different characters (Freema Agyeman/Martha Jones as Adeola Oshodi in “Army of Ghosts” (s2) and Karen Gillan/Amy Pond as a soothsayer in “The Fires of Pompeii” (s4)), I do not think this is such a case.  It was known that Jenna-Louise Coleman was going to be the new companion long before “Asylum Of The Daleks” was finished.  Assuming Oswin is the new companion, I am concerned this is going to be another River Song-type story.  That is, The Doctor will meet her earlier in her life and travel with her while knowing how she will die.  You could argue that Oswin did not know The Doctor in “Asylum,” but I think she is good enough to be able to lie to The Doctor.  The whole “remember me” thing at the end definitely made me think she at least knew who she was.  This would be kind of annoying, but not surprising as Moffat has a history of reusing his storylines (Amelia's situation in “The Eleventh Hour” (s5) was about the same as Reinette's in “The Girl In The Fireplaec” (s2)).
				</p>
				<p>
					There is another interesting theory I have heard: Oswin was “assimilated” (to use the <i>Star Trek</i> term) by the Daleks and had access to the hive mind of all the Daleks, not just the ones in the asylum.  Therefore it is reasonable to conclude the Daleks have complete access to her mind as well.  It is possible the Daleks may create a copy of Oswin (we have had no shortage of clones in recent <i>Who</i> history--nearly every companion in new <i>Who</i> has had some sort of duplicate made*).  That duplicate could either be part of a Dalek plan from which The Doctor rescues her, or she could be set up to meet The Doctor as <i>part</i> of a Dalek plan.  In the latter case, since the Daleks have joined other residents of the universe in asking, “Doctor Who,” it is possible that Oswin might be part of a plan that leads The Doctor to the fields of Trenzalore.
				</p>
				<p style="font-size:smaller;">
					*Martha by the Sontarans in “The Sontaran Stratagem”/“The Poison Sky” (s4); Donna's mind in the Doctor-Donna in “Journey's End” (s4); Amy by the Flesh some time around the end of “Day Of The Moon” (s6), revealed in “The Almost People” (s6); Rory by the Nestene in “The Pandorica Opens”/“The Big Bang” (s5).
				</p>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2012 22:20:00 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>AndRant: Google Music for Jelly Bean</title>
			<link>http://zmyaro.com/blog/post.html#2012-07-18</link>
			<description>
				<p>
					You may remember I ranted a bit about my experience with the leaked pre-release version of Google Music.  Since then a lot has changed in the app, and today Google released the “harder, better, faster, stronger” (according to the update news) Android 4.1 (Jelly Bean/JB) version of Google Music for Android (still compatible with pre-JB devices, of course).  A lot has changed since the 4.0 (Ice Cream Sandwich/ICS) version; in fact, in terms of functionality, this might be the most major change to the Android music experience since the Music app became Google Music.  This is good in some ways and annoying in other ways.  I have actually been using the app for a couple weeks (since Google I/O day), and these are my impressions.
				</p>
				<p>
					<a href="http://zmyaro.com/imgs/blog/2012/07/18/widget.png" target="_blank"><img src="http://zmyaro.com/imgs/blog/2012/07/18/widget.png" alt="The new Google Music home screen widget" /></a>
					Let us start with the good.  I have used the Music home screen widget since I first started using my old Droid a couple years ago, and this is the first major change it has seen on phones.  In addition to the current song and artist names, play/pause button, and next song button, the widget now includes album art and a thumbs up button.  I would personally prefer a rewind/previous song button over the thumbs up button, but I still think the updated widget is a fantastic improvement.
				</p>
				<p style="clear:right;">
					<a href="http://zmyaro.com/imgs/blog/2012/07/18/recent.png" target="_blank"><img src="http://zmyaro.com/imgs/blog/2012/07/18/recent.png" alt="The new recent music page, with the new playlist art, bottom action bar, and navigation header pointed out" /></a>
					The UI of the app itself has also seen some improvements.  While the old bottom action bar design minimized the space taken up by action bars, the new look maintains consistency across views and device types.  The addition of a top action bar on phones means the bottom action bar can now contain music controls—a feature that was removed in the ICS version to make room for the search and action overflow buttons.  Unfortunately, this UI change removed the tabs that used to occupy the top of the portrait UI in favor of using swipe gestures to switch pages.  What is irritating is, unlike the phone landscape or tablet UIs, there is no drop down list of pages, so getting from one page to another can take up to five swipes where it used to take a single tab press.  Hopefully that will be improved in a later update.
				</p>
				<p>
					Another improvement is the new recent music page.  In landscape mode on phones and in both orientations on tablets, it shows a 3D carosel of albums and playlists, but in portrait orientation on phones it used to show a simple list.  Now, instead, the portrait view contains large album and playlist images.  And on that note, playlist images are now made up of album art from the songs they contain—a major improvement.
				</p>
				<p style="clear:right;">
					<img src="http://zmyaro.com/imgs/blog/2012/07/18/honeycomb.png" alt="Song/album/artist names on Google Music for Android 3.x" />
					Another change (note that I do not refer to this one as an “improvement”) is to the Now Playing screen.  There are certainly improvements here.  For instance, additional controls fade in without needing to resize the album art (which was an annoyingly laggy animation on older devices).  But those improvements are overshadowed by lost functionality.  Since the first Music app in Android 1, it has been possible to long-press a song, album, or artist name to search for it on the web or in other apps like YouTube, Pandora, etc.  The first Google Music app (seen on an Android 3.x (Honeycomb) device in the screenshot) improved on this by letting you add a song to a playlist, view the whole album, or view all your albums by the artist, by tapping the song, album, or artist, respectively.  Finally, every version of the app since Android 1 has let you slide a song/album/artist name horizontally to see the rest of it if it is too long to fit on the screen.  This latest update removes all those features and, in most cases, offers no alternative ways to perform those actions.  There is only one reason I can think of for this change, which is it makes the UI more similar to the iPhone/iPod Touch music app, with basic controls at the bottom, big album art in the middle, seek/shuffle/repeat hidden by default, back button at the upper-left, and queue button at the upper-right.
				</p>
				<p>
					That brings me to the most major change in this update: Google has brought back the now playing queue.  Surprisingly, I do not approve.  I say surprisingly because when the Android Music app becaume Google Music, it removed the now playing queue, and that was one of my biggest complaints.  There are two reasons I am not happy to see it return.
				</p>
				<p>
					The first is that, as of ICS, the Google Music app was doing fine without it.  Sure, it was unpleasant on the first Google Music app for Android 2.3 (Gingerbread), but when ICS came along and standardized the “up” button as a means of navigation, everything got simpler.  If you started playing a song from an album, pressing the Google Music icon at the upper-left of the now playing screen would take you to that album.  If you started playing a song from a playlist, pressing the icon would take you to the playlist and scroll you to that song.  Updating that playlist meant updating the current queue.  In the new version of Google Music, pressing the Google Music icon from the now playing screen takes you back to the recent music screen, and if you add a song to the playlist you started from, you have to add it to the queue separately.
				</p>
				<p>
					The second reason I am not happy to see the now playing queue return is that it is buggy and unpredictable.  For instance, let us say you tapped a song in an album earlier in the day.  The app automatically added the rest of the album to the queue.  That makes sense.  Now, hours later, you select a song from a playlist.  That playlist gets added to the queue, <em>but the album you listened to earlier is still there</em>.  If you do not make a habit of clearing your queue before playing a new playlist, it can become a mess.
				</p>
				<p>
					This gets worse when you bring shuffle into the picture.  Let us say you have nothing in your queue and you select the first song in an album.  The album should start playing and, assuming shuffle is off, the rest of the album should be in the queue, in order.
					<br />
					<a href="http://zmyaro.com/imgs/blog/2012/07/18/shuffle_bug1.png" target="_blank"><img src="http://zmyaro.com/imgs/blog/2012/07/18/shuffle_bug1.png" class="fill" /></a>
					<br />
					Now you decide to enable shuffle.  Rather than the app moving to a random point in the queue when the song changes, as it has in every previous version of Music, it randomizes the order of items in the queue.  Not quite what I am used to, but acceptable.
					<br />
					<a href="http://zmyaro.com/imgs/blog/2012/07/18/shuffle_bug2.png" target="_blank"><img src="http://zmyaro.com/imgs/blog/2012/07/18/shuffle_bug2.png" class="fill" /></a>
					<br />
					Here is where things get strange.  If you then disable shuffle, the queue remains randomized rather than returning to its original order.
					<br />
					<a href="http://zmyaro.com/imgs/blog/2012/07/18/shuffle_bug3.png" target="_blank"><img src="http://zmyaro.com/imgs/blog/2012/07/18/shuffle_bug3.png" class="fill" /></a>
					<br />
					Combine that with the fact that selecting an item in a different album or playlist adds the whole playlist to the queue, and you can imagine how weird it can get to have parts of the queue shuffled and parts unshuffled (even more so when tracks get added by selecting Menu → Shuffle all on an album or playlist).
				</p>
				<p>
					So there you have it.  The latest version of Google Music for Android brings, among other things, some highly-requested features (including better playlist images), UI changes (updated home screen widget, consistent top action bar, music controls on bottom action bar, new Now Playing screen), and the return of the now playing queue.  If you have an Android 2.2+ device, go ahead and download the latest version from <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.google.android.music" target="_blank">Google Play</a>.
				</p>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2012 20:50:00 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Bits-A-Me, brentalfloss!</title>
			<link>http://zmyaro.com/blog/post.html#2012-07-12</link>
			<description>
				<p>
					So <i>finally</i>, after months of delays, I received my physical copy of brentalfloss's new CD, “Bits Of Me.”  This CD has been delayed so long since its original release date (which felt even longer to me, since I pre-ordered it) that Level Up ended up giving me a digital copy, but now I finally have the real signed physical disc.
				</p>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2012 18:50:00 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>&lt;/downtime&gt;</title>
			<link>http://zmyaro.com/blog/post.html#2012-07-08</link>
			<description>
				<p>
					As you might have heard, we on the east coast U.S. were just hit by one of the worst summer storms in recent years (at least in terms of damage).  I am fine, as are my friends (the car I drove home from the storm in...slightly less so...), but we were without electricity and running water for several days.  Thankfully, unlike snowmageddon a couple years ago, we could actually drive out.  Anyway, now, only a few days after Amazon, my downtime has ended.  Hope everyone else made it through the storm okay.
				</p>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2012 15:20:00 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>I Am Back!</title>
			<link>http://zmyaro.com/blog/post.html#2012-06-02</link>
			<description>
				<p>
					Hello, everyone,
					<br/>
					<img src="http://30.media.tumblr.com/tumblr_ls1meqYsgp1qhgzjro1_400.gif" alt="I'm back!" class="fill" />
				</p>
				<p>
					I finally did what I should have done long ago: bought a domain (thankfully zmyaro.com is not something anyone else would want to buy), set up a server and just hosted my site myself.  The downside is that means my site being up is dependent on me having working power (now that I have acknowledged that, prepare for record-breaking storms) and Internet, but the positive side is that I control everything, meaning I can build on top of whatever backend I want rather than being limited to static files (ugh).  To start, I am planning to rewrite my blog in PHP, which I expect to take several months (well, no, it will take a couple hours or days at most, but it will be interrupted by things like my job, social life, and other projects).  Eventually I am thinking of rewriting the whole site in NodeJS, but that will probably not happen for a while.  So...yeah, that is the state of things wrt my website.
				</p>
				<p>
					Oh, and for those who care about such things, the server is running Apache on Arch Linux.  [EDIT] The server is no longer on Arch.
				</p>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 02 June 2012 19:50:00 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Update-less Update</title>
			<link>http://zmyaro.com/blog/post.html#2012-01-11</link>
			<description>
				<p>
					As some of you might be aware, Verizon took away FTP access to personal websites a few months ago, which is the primary reason I stopped updating.  Some exciting stuff has happened since then, and I will hopefully post about that soon.  Unfortunately, I am also dealing with a ton of school-related stuff, but once first semester ends and I get all my college apps in (i.e. February), I will have much more time to devote to this (I am not saying that is when updates will start happening, just that that is the soonest I might have time).  If you want more content from me more frequently, you can circle me on <a href="http://profiles.google.com/zmyaro" target="_blank">Google+</a>.
				</p>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2012 19:50:00 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Plaguing The Interwebz</title>
			<link>http://zmyaro.com/blog/post.html#2011-04-19,googlewave.com!w+Akj2G-VqA</link>
			<description>
				<p>
					Every few years at my family's Pesach seder I have created something electronic to go along with the ten plagues.  Usually it was a PowerPoint presentation or an animation of some sort.  This year I decided to do something on a larger scale.  I decided that I would plague <i>the entire Internet</i>.  MUHAHAHAHA!! [insert stock footage of kittens running in fear as lightning flashes in the background]
				</p>
				<p>
					I have created a Chrome extension that, when installed, will inflict one of the plagues on every webpage you visit.  For legal reasons I could not <i>actually</i> kill the webmaster's first-born child, but all the plagues are in there...in some form or another.
				</p>
				<p>
					You can get the extension <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/kmcopldlooadgljinjpljijdmmgkjdlp" target="_blank">here</a>.  If you have Firefox or another decent, but non-Chrome browser, you can still try this out using my Ten Plagues bookmarklet, which can be found on my <a href="projects/chrome/index.html" target="_blank">extensions</a> page.
				</p>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2011 20:50:00 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Update: New Visual Style</title>
			<link>http://zmyaro.com/blog/post.html#2011-03-09,googlewave.com!w+cU-6uW66C</link>
			<description>
				<p>
					I have been talking about and working on this for a while, but now I finally finished my website's new visual style.  The wave theme was nice, but I have gotten bored of it.  The new look has a clear electronic look to it, which better reflects my interests.  In addition, each section of my website has a color associated with it, which can help you see where you are.
				</p>
				<p>
					I hope you like the new theme.  Oh, and happy <i>Brawl</i> day :)
				</p>
				<p style="font-size:smaller;">
					(The fact that this update is happening on the anniversary of <i>Brawl</i>'s North American release is a coincidence, but a good one :P)
				</p>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2011 18:42:00 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Review: Inception, second viewing</title>
			<link>http://zmyaro.com/blog/post.html#2011-01-17,googlewave.com!w+87N6EIdQA</link>
			<description>
				<p>
					When I first saw <i>Inception</i>, I thought it was awesome, but was not worth seeing more than once.  I discovered yesterday that I was definitely wrong.  Obviously a little bit of the fun is lost when you know what is going to happen instead of trying to figure out who is in whose dream.  But there is so much in the movie that I still found myself noticing plenty of things that I missed before or forgot about, and it is difficult to not still be impressed by the attention to detail in the huge dream worlds.  Even if you already saw <i>Inception</i>, I highly recommend renting the DVD/Blu-Ray.
				</p>
				<p>
					Here are some of the things I learned from watching <i>Inception</i>:
					<ul>
						<li>Zombies in your head can be just as bad as zombies in your house</li>
						<li>Out-of-control existentialism causes problems</li>
						<li>Christopher Nolan is a genius</li>
					</ul>
				</p>
				<p>
					<b>My rating:</b>
					<br/>
					Story: 5/7
					<br/>
					<span style="margin-left:18px; display:inline-block;">
						The overall story was good, but many of the characters lacked depth
					</span>
					<br/>
					<br/>
					Visuals: 7/7
					<br/>
					<span style="margin-left:18px; display:inline-block;">
						The unique dream worlds looked incredible.  In addition, one trick that was particularly impressive was after Fischer gets out of the van with Browning: the camera pans so Browning is behind Fischer and when you see him he looks Eames again.
					</span>
					<br/>
					<br/>
					Music: 7/7
					<br/>
					<span style="margin-left:18px; display:inline-block;">
						Hans Zimmer.  'nuff said.
					</span>
					<br/>
					<br/>
					Overall: 7/7
					<br/>
					<span style="margin-left:18px; display:inline-block;">
						This is easily one of the best movies ever made.
					</span>
				</p>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2011 21:07:15 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Update: Return of the Rants</title>
			<link>http://zmyaro.com/blog/post.html#2011-01-09,googlewave.com!w+P0MMHGTRA</link>
			<description>
				<p>
					I have not posted anything in a LONG time.  This is primarily because of school taking up most of my time and my various other projects taking up the rest.  But during this time I have typed up some rants about various subjects that I intend to post over the next few weeks.  Keep in mind that some of these were written as far back as last September, so they may refer to things that have already happened in the theoretical or future tense.
				</p>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2011 22:00:15 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>I Am Still Alive</title>
			<link>http://zmyaro.com/blog/post.html#2010-11-27,googlewave.com!w+DrTNEyzbA</link>
			<description>
				<p>
					First off, I want to make it clear that this post contains no <i>Portal</i> references, despite the title.  Okay, on to the post.
				</p>
				<p>
					I realize that I have not been posting much on the site recently.  The main reason for this is school, but I also have several other projects that have taken priority over my site.  Unfortunately this will continue to be the case for a while, but I do have some things I wrote over the past couple months that I hope to post at some point.  In addition, you can follow <a href="http://google.com/profiles/zmyaro#buzz">my buzz</a>.
				</p>
				<p>
					Now on to the next part.  HAPPY <span style="font-size:8pt">late</span> THANKSGIVING!  Well, assuming you live in the U.S.; otherwise happy Thursday-earlier-this-week.  I actually just got home last night from visiting my mother's family.  I know a ton of people are going to ask if I got the "enhanced pat-down".  Actually going through security was possibly the easiest it has ever been since TSA insanity started.  This was the case for both my flight leaving and coming back.  I do have one complaint however.  I happened to see the touch-screen controls for the X-ray scanner and they looked like Windows 3.  With how much those machines probably cost, is a pretty UI too much to ask?
				</p>
				<p>
					That is all for now.  Hopefully I will post more soon.  Particularly my review of the new <i>Harry Potter</i> movie (it is awesome).  I also have some other ideas on how to keep my website active.  For now, you should still be able to find me on Buzz on Wave.
				</p>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2010 18:35:15 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Update: Better Organization</title>
			<link>http://zmyaro.com/blog/post.html#2010-09-06,googlewave.com!w+TNC8BHXrD</link>
			<description>
				<p>
					I am returning to school tomorrow.  On one hand I am excited to go back because it is so awesome (please do not kill me, antimatter15), but on the other hand I still have things I meant to do this summer that I never finished.  Oh well.
				</p>
				<p>
					On a related note, going to school means I will only have one computer (and by "computer" I mean laptop or bigger; Droids do not count) with me.  So my old broken Windows laptop will not be coming with me to school.  This of course means that I need Linux and Windows on the same computer.  So I just had a fun time this weekend cleaning off my hard drive (which I discovered is 20 GB smaller than it is advertised to be) and reinstalling OSes.  Twice.  Fun fun fun.  But now everything works better than before.  Also funny thing: it took over an hour to install Windows and a long time (I do not remember exactly) to install the 70 or so updates, but it only took under 15 minutes to install Linux and less than that to install the >250 updates.  And before you say it, Sreenath, shut up.
				</p>
				<p>
					On another note related related to the start of school, I began writing a parody back in June (it was actually while I was in Israel, so if anyone from the trip saw me typing on my Droid, I might have been working on this).  I had intended to finish it in time for the start of school, but I still have lyrics I have not come up with.  It is yet another AVPM parody (I really need to find another source XD), and another "Get Back To Hogwarts" parody, except this time I have parodied essentially the entire scene.
				</p>
				<p>
					Aaanyway, like I said it still is not done, but I have a good chunk done (although not all polished), so I am going to put it out.  Kind of like the "Get Back To TJ" canary build.  And a funny thing is I bet none of my friends who have seen AVPM get what I mean by canary build.
				</p>
				<p>

					Aaaanyway, <a href="htty://zmyaro.com/projects/parodies/parody.html#googlewave.com!w+TNC8BHXrA" target="_blank">it is there</a>.  Enjoy.  Comment if you like it.  Comment if you do not.  Comment if you feel like commenting.  I will try to post again as soon as I have time.
				</p>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2010 21:25:00 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Update: Better Organization</title>
			<link>http://zmyaro.com/blog/post.html#2010-08-28,googlewave.com!w+aa4j93kEB</link>
			<description>
				<p>
					I mentioned <a href="news_static.html#2010-08-09,googlewave.com!w+i3jfPHc8A" target="_blank">a few weeks ago</a> that I was renaming my "My Stuff" section to "Projects".  I never quite finished making the change across my whole site, but as of today, I think I have fixed all the old links.  Also note that I am removing the "mystuff" folder because I am running low on free space.  And for the same reason, I may be switching where my website is hosted (feel free to comment with recommendations).
				</p>
				<p>
					Also, I have created a new section called "Me" to separate pages talking about me from pages talking about my creations.  It currently contains what used to be My Stuff > About Me and My Stuff > F.A.Q.
				</p>
				<p>
					Finally, I have added the navigation bar icons to more pages.  Up to this point I have gotten only positive feedback, so I guess it was a good change (and it certainly looks nicer than a plain list).
				</p>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2010 15:25:00 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Update: Better Commenting</title>
			<link>http://zmyaro.com/blog/post.html#2010-08-21,googlewave.com!w+1zWDQzUgF</link>
			<description>
				<img src="imgs/news/anony_comments.png" alt="Anony-Comments" style="float:right;"/>
				<p>
					In the past, commenting on my blog-like news feed has been limited to Google Wave users in browsers supported by Google Wave (Chrome, Safari, and Firefox).  Thanks to a <a href="http://antimatter15.com/wp/2010/06/wave-embed-api/" target="_blank">new tool</a> from antimatter15 <big style="font-weight:bold;">now anyone can comment from any<small>*</small> browser</big>.  When you click the "View static" link, comments will be displayed if available and you can post from there.  The UI is simple and should look familiar to long-time wave users.
				</p>
				<p>
					In addition, through use of antimatter15's Anony-Bot, you can comment even if you do not have a Google Wave account.  The only downside is that you will not get Wave's real-time communication.  If you want live typing and the ability to post from your wave account, just choose the "View as wave" option (formerly "View with comments").  Happy commenting!
				</p>
				<small>*assuming my website supports it, meaning no IE</small>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2010 01:01:30 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Update: My Site, Re-Themed (Save Wave, Part 4)</title>
			<link>http://zmyaro.com/blog/post.html#2010-08-15,googlewave.com!w+lS1ah2yjd</link>
			<description>
				<p>
					My site has been re-themed to look like Google Wave as part of my Save Google Wave work.  This also shows off how easy it is to use code from my <a href="projects/wave/ui.html" target="_blank">wave UI CSS</a> in another web site's stylesheet.
				</p>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2010 04:14:10 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>More Projects!  (A.K.A. Save Wave, Part 3)</title>
			<link>http://zmyaro.com/blog/post.html#2010-08-09,googlewave.com!w+i3jfPHc8A</link>
			<description>
				<p>
					In case you have not noticed, I am renaming the "My Stuff" section to "Projects".  URLs going to the mystuff folder will work for a little while until I update all the links to it, but after that I will only keep the installer and gadget XML for my Yes/No/Mini gadget, which some waves depend on.  With this "new" section comes new stuff!  And since I am still SaveGoogleWave-crazed, they are wave-related:
				</p>
				<p>
					The <a href="projects/wave/ui.html" target="_blank">first</a> has been up for a little over a day.  It is some CSS3 that offers a (I think) better alternative to wave.ui in gadgets and can also be used on other websites and web apps.  Feel free to link to the <a href="projects/wave/ui.css" target="_blank">stylesheet</a> or copy out what you need.  If you want to be nice, you can credit me for writing the CSS, but remember that the Google Wave team originally designed the UI.
				</p>
				<img src="projects/chrome/wave_reply.png" style="vertical-align:top; float:right;" alt="Wave Reply thumbnail"/>
				<p>
					The <a href="projects/chrome/index.html#wave_reply" target="_blank">second</a> is less for developers and more for users.  It is a bookmarklet that you can click when reading a message in Gmail to turn the message into a wave.
				</p>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2010 01:17:20 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Save Wave, Part 2</title>
			<link>http://zmyaro.com/blog/post.html#2010-08-07</link>
			<description>
				<p>
					As part of my effort to save Google Wave, I have written a new lyric.  You can view it on my website <a href="projects/parodies/parody.html#googlewave.com!w+DEKziLZkG6" target="_blank">here</a> or <a href="https://wave.google.com/wave/waveref/googlewave.com/w+DEKziLZkG6" target="_blank">on Google Wave</a>.
				</p>
				<p>
					So make a joyful sound
					<br/>
					'cause Google Wave ain't goin' down!
				</p>

			</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2010 16:05:00 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>SAVE THE WAVE!</title>
			<link>http://zmyaro.com/blog/post.html#2010-08-05</link>
			<description>
				<img src="imgs/save_wave.png" style="float:left; margin-right:8px;" title="Save Google Wave at savegooglewave.com!" alt="Save Google Wave!"/>
				<p>
					You may have seen or heard about Google's announcement that they will be getting rid of Google Wave by the end of this year.  My initial response was "NOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOO!!!!!!!!"  Please go to <a href="http://www.savegooglewave.com" target="_blank">savegooglewave.com</a> and show your support for Google Wave.  Let us not give up on this incredible product, platform, and protocol!
				</p>
				<br/>
				<p style="font-size:10pt;">
					To quote <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sKfya5VmmYg&amp;hd=1" target="_blank" style="font-style:italic;">A Very Potter Sequel</a>:
					<br/>
					<br/>
					There's no way
					<br/>
					we're gonna leave it up to chance,
					<br/>
					there's no damn way we're gonna go without a fight!
					<br/>
					No way you gonna see us on on our ass,
					<br/>
					There's no, no way...
					<br/>
					<br/>
					There's no way
					<br/>
					we're gonna settle with sorrow,
					<br/>
					leave right now if you think this ain't real!
					<br/>
					Today, not waitin' for tomorrow!
					<br/>
					<br/>
					No, no way there's no way,
					<br/>
					no, no way there's no way,
					<br/>
					no, no way there's no way,
					<br/>
					THERE'S
					<br/>
					NO
					<br/>
					WAY!
				</p>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2010 19:27:00 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Update: More More Extensions!</title>
			<link>http://zmyaro.com/blog/post.html#2010-08-03</link>
			<description>
				<img src="oldnews_imgs/wave_logo.png" style="float:right;" alt="Google Wave logo"/>
				I randomly decided to learn the wave gadgets and extension APIs.  My initial project, the time zone gadget is still being worked on, although you are certainly free to try it.  My other gadget is the <a href="https://wave.google.com/wave/waveref/googlewave.com/w+OnAgVLZkfT" target="_blank">Yes/No/Mini gadget</a>.  This one is just a miniature version of the Yes/No/Maybe gadget and as of about an hour and a half ago it was approved and added to the extensions gallery!  You can view all my wave extensions (with links to the installers, demo waves, and gadget XML) on <a href="projects/wave/index.html">this page</a>.  More will be coming when I have an idea, see a need, or get a request.
			</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2010 02:50:30 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Update: More Extensions!</title>
			<link>http://zmyaro.com/blog/post.html#2010-07-15</link>
			<description>
				I have reorganized and added some more <a href="projects/chrome/index.html" target="_blank">Chrome extensions</a> (some of which work in browsers other than Chrome).  One of the new additions is a bookmarklet that allows you to open a wave being viewed it the Google Wave client in a new window.  One other one may be coming in the next few days.  And if you are interested in getting more extension-related updates, you can follow <a href="https://wave.google.com/wave/waveref/googlewave.com/w+HEEsmGFNA" target="_blank">this wave</a>.
			</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2010 16:14:30 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Observation: The Reason For The Nexus One?</title>
			<link>http://zmyaro.com/blog/post.html#2010-07-14</link>
			<description>
				I, like many people, am seeing the Nexus One as a failure.  Google's web store failed, Google's plan to sell it through every carrier failed, and the phone did not even stay the top phone for very long.  I recently read a statement claiming that the point of the N1 was to drive innovation in Android phone hardware.  And when you think about it, within months the HTC Incredible and Evo were released and just recently the Droid X, all of which have 1 GHz processors, two of which have large screens and can take and output HD video, and all of which have overall better hardware than the N1 or iPhone 4.  Do I believe that this was Google's only motive or even its primary one?  Of course not, but at least the N1 did accomplish something.
			</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2010 13:48:00 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Rant: My Responses To The Engi Update</title>
			<link>http://zmyaro.com/blog/post.html#2010-07-13</link>
			<description>
				<p>
					I came back from Israel to find in my <i>Team Fortress 2</i> blog feed.that the Engineer Update had happened while I was gone (how convenient).  It had been several months since I last played TF2 and since Engi is my favorite class I figured this was a good time to start playing again.  I was somewhat surprised by the new UI, but I did not have any problems with it.  My only complaint is that I wish windows, like the server list and achievements list could be collapsed so I could reach the buttons behind them.
				</p>
				<p>
					When I actually started playing, I was surprised to discover that I had nothing big to complain about.  I still remember all the problems that occurred around the Sniper vs. Spy update, but it would seem that the random drop system has been made more fair, the backpack and crafting systems have had the major bugs fixed, and the new Engi items have been added (for the most part) without any major issues.  My congratulations to Valve for finally getting it right.
				</p>
				<p>
					One thing I particularly liked about this update was that it was for the Engineer--my favorite class, meaning a class I actually play, unlike the last few (soldier, demo, sniper).  And unlike those, I did not have to work toward specific achievements.  Things like upgrading and repairing teammates' buildings, resupplying their sentries, teleporting hundreds of people to the front lines, racing to buildings to remove sappers, and picking up old sentry and dispenser bits to use as building metal are all things I do anyway.  Which I suppose is what Valve had in mind.

				</p>
				<p>
					I was not particularly thrilled about the new items.  Not that they are not good choices, but they are not quite what <i>I</i> had hoped for.  The Frontier Justice seems useful in some cases, but more often then not it is an explosion that destroys my sentry the same explosion kills me as well.  The Gunslinger to me is useless.  I am certainly not willing to give up the power of a full level 3 sentry.  Although thre mini sentry seems eerily similar to the “Jiffy Gun,” which some other players and I discussed on the TF2 forums several months back, except that you only are allowed one mini-sentry.  The Wrangler is one I am somewhat uncertain about.  I like the idea of being able to control where my sentry aims (and being able to hit enemies shooting it from outside its normal range), but the delay in switching back to automatic aiming, the big laser beam and bright bubble calling attention to my sentry and the way I have seen some Engis chew through ammo and run out in the middle of a swarm is enough to keep me on the fence about the Wrangler.  But again, Valve wants there to be upsides and downsides to each weapon.
				</p>
				<p>
					Overall I would consider this to be one of the most (if not the most) successful class update, and probably my favorite.
				</p>				
			</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2010 23:10:00 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Rant: My Thoughts On The "Google Me" Rumor</title>
			<link>http://zmyaro.com/blog/post.html#2010-06-29</link>
			<description>
				<p>
					For those who care, I am going to be away from home without my computer for a little while, so my site is not going to be updated for a little while.  On the bright side, this will not cause the end of the world.  Now on to the real post.
				</p>
				<p>
					Rumor has it Google intends to release a new social networking platform called "Google Me."  Here are some of my thoughts:
				</p>
				<p>
					A good part of my online life is run through Google.  I use Gmail, Google Talk, Google Calendar, Google Wave, Google Reader, Android, and of course Google search many times a day.  And then there is Facebook.  That one app that is different.  The app that looks different, works different, has its buttons in different places, and that I do not particularly like and only really use because of people who refuse to use anything else.
				</p>
				<p>
					I would personally love it if Google could make a Facebook-like app with a Googley simple interface and that integrates seamlessly with the other Google apps I use.  My Buzz and Reader shared items could be pulled in and shared with my Gmail/Gtalk/Gwave/Android contacts.  That would be great!
				</p>
				<p>
					One issue:
					<br/>
					They kinda already tried that.
				</p>
				<p>
					A little app called Orkut.  An app that was supposed to be Google's social networking platform but was so unsuccessful that its name is not even built into Google's Android dictionary ("Facebook" is).  As nice as these "Google Me" rumors sound, I am wondering if Google is ready to challenge Facebook again.  If it does, it had better have something really good ready.
				</p>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2010 13:28:00 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Update: F.A.Q. You!</title>
			<link>http://zmyaro.com/blog/post.html#2010-06-26</link>
			<description>
				I have added <a href="projects/faq.html" target="_blank">a page of questions</a> I am tired of answering.  In other news, I have made a <a href="https://wave.google.com/wave/waveref/googlewave.com/w+96gSZIgqH" target="_blank">wave version</a> of my news page.  Now you can follow my blog-like news feed via wave, RSS, or by checking the site regularly.  Finally, I have cleaned up my home page a bit by moving the subscription buttons to the news page.
			</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2010 19:03:30 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Update: More Of My Stuff</title>
			<link>http://zmyaro.com/blog/post.html#2010-06-08</link>
			<description>
				More content is being added to the <a href="projects/index.html">my stuff</a> section.  I recently added a page with two of my Chrome extensions (another one or two should be coming soon...ish).  In addition, today I added a page with some parodies I have written.  Congratulations, you now know I like to write parodies! +10 XP!  With this comes the completion of project 8779, which is...a parody!  Specifically one of a song that has been in my head since the J-Day theme (Harry Potter) was announced.  Sorry to non-TRSTYites who may not like it as much.
			</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2010 21:12:30 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Google I/O Day 2 Predictions</title>
			<link>http://zmyaro.com/blog/news_wave.html#googlewave.com!w+X_FCZv6gD</link>
			<description>
				[only available in wave form]
			</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2010 21:57:50</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Update: News</title>
			<link>http://zmyaro.com/blog/post.html#2010-05-05</link>
			<description>
				As you may have noticed, I have updated the news page.  It is now at <span style="text-decoration: line-through;">http://zmyaro.com/news.html</span><a href="https://zmyaro.com/blog">[EDIT] zmyaro.com/blog</a> (yes, three letters shorter!).  The posts are now listed by date and give you options to view them as plain HTML or in a wave with comments.  Not displaying every post on one page makes it easier to go through the list and makes it easier to read a single post.  The links in the RSS feed will now link to the HTML version since wave lags on some computers.  And speaking of waves, I have updated the wave view to work with the new embedding API.  This means that you can now view the comments in the wave <b>without logging into your wave account</b>.  Unfortunately right now the embedded wave is required to have a blue border and white background, so it does not blend in with the site like it used to, but hopefully Google will fix that soon.
				<br/>
				<br/>
				I know I say this every time, but I really do have other stuff I will post soon, but school and work take up a lot of time!
			</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2010 22:00:00</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Education Kills Creativity</title>
			<link>http://zmyaro.com/blog/post.html#2010-02-15</link>
			<description>
				A friend of mine told me about this video and I found it quite interesting--and accurate.
				<br/>
				<br/>
				<a href="http://zmyaro.com/blog/post.html#2010-02-15">[Video Player]</a>
				<br/>
				<br/>
				<a href="http://www.ted.com/talks/ken_robinson_says_schools_kill_creativity.html">http://www.ted.com/talks/ken_robinson_says_schools_kill_creativity.html</a>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2010 17:50:00</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Update: MASSIVE Update</title>
			<link>http://zmyaro.com/blog/post.html#2010-01-13</link>
			<description>
				Happy new year!  If you go to my home page, you will see that it has changed significantly.  The changes include:
				<ul>
					<li>
						New layout
					</li>
					<ul>
						<li>
							The navigation box has moved to a navigation bar on the left.  This navigation bar can be minimized for people with smaller screens.
						</li>
						<li>
							There is now a sidebar to the right which, for the moment, contains my shared items from Google Reader and buttons related to my news feed.  I will probably add more things to it in the future.
						</li>
					</ul>
					<li>
						The navigation bar is now a bit more organized.  Links to parts of my site are organized alphabetically.  External links are sorted in an order I like :P
					</li>
					<li>
						I have finally added the "My Stuff" section.  Anyone who can read my mind/hacked my computer would know that I have been wanting to add this section for a while.  I was just not sure what to put in it.  Right now it contains a few apps I wrote, but other stuff will be coming soon (like within-a-week "soon", not my usual "soon").
					</li>
					<li>
						Comments on news posts are now viewable (but not yet editable) by non-wave users thanks to an awesome (and extremely fast) wave reader by Antimatter15.
					</li>
					<li>
						And on the code side of things
						<ul>
							<li>
								My home page has been updated to HTML5.  This does not mean much on the user interface side of things (yet), but things like the <code>&lt;nav&gt;</code> and <code>&lt;footer&gt;</code> tags help bots make more sense of the page.  Unfortunately this may cause a few problems for Internet Explorer users (IE is the only modern browser that does not support HTML5), but this can be solved with <a href="http://code.google.com/chrome/chromeframe/">Google Chrome Frame</a>.
							</li>
							<li>
								I am organizing my stylesheets better to make formatting more consistant across the site (exceptions include certain computer help and video game pages).
							</li>
						</ul>
					</li>
				</ul>
				I hope to bring some of the improvements (especially the navigation bar) to other parts of my site.  Please let me know what you think of the changes be e-mailing me at <a href="mailto:zmyaro@gmail.com">zmyaro@gmail.com</a> or waving me at <span class="fakelink">zmyaro@googlewave.com</span>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2010 06:30:00</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Update: Scorp on Docs</title>
			<link>http://zmyaro.com/blog/post.html#2009-12-02</link>
			<description>I finally got around to uploading the <a href="star_trek/scorp/index.html">Scorp dictionaries</a> to Google Docs.  Now you can view them online anywhere (assuming that "anywhere" has Internet).  Also, I am working on a larger update to the site in my free time.  Unfortunately I do not have much of that, so the update may not come as soon as I would like and might be released in smaller pieces rather than all at once.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2009 22:12:26</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>News: Comments</title>
			<link>http://zmyaro.com/blog/post.html#2009-11-03</link>
			<description>Wow, three posts in one week.  I am on a roll here!  Anyway, I wanted to point out that I am testing a system for commenting on news posts.  You may remember when I tried putting all the news posts on a wave and that did not work very well.  I am trying a new system that will not have posts in waves, but will instead use waves for just the comments.  If you have a Google Wave preview (not dev preview this time), take a look <a href="oldnews-wave.html">here</a>.  Currently only the three most recent posts have commenting available.  In the future I may add comment waves to older posts if people request it.  Please note that you may not add bots or gadgets to these comment waves (unless approved by me).  Also, please do not say anything offensive in your comments.  I will edit/remove any inappropriate comments.</description>  Finally, remember that this is just a test, so do not expect it to be perfect!
			<pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2009 16:38:53</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Observation: Droid Lies?</title>
			<link>http://zmyaro.com/blog/post.html#2009-11-02</link>
			<description>I have been looking into the new Verizon Droid phone recently (mainly because of interest in the Android 2.0 OS)  while on the <a href="http://www.droiddoes.com">Droid website</a>, I happened to notice something.  Right there under the big "Turn-By-Turn Nav".  <a href="oldnews_imgs/droid_multi_touch.png">"Multi touch"</a>.  This is strange, because the Droid does <i>not</i> support multi-touch, so why would it be mentioned on the site?</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2009 22:10:17 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Observations: Companies' Responses To Windows 7</title>
			<link>http://zmyaro.com/blog/post.html#2009-10-30</link>
			<description>
				The Windows 7 RC has been available for over seven months now, but people are just starting to modify their applications to take advantage of Windows 7's features.  Here are some I find particularly useful.
				<ul>
					<li>
						Google Chrome takes over the default title bar, but since reasonably early this year it has supported Aero Snap (allowing a window to be restored by dragging the title bar down when the window is maximized, and resizing it in various ways by dragging it to different edges of the screen).  It has even added similar features for tabs.  Also, a bit more recently Chrome has gotten its own custom jump list (the menu you see when you right-click a program on your taskbar) with the ability to open a new standard or incognito window or to open a commonly visited or recently closed page.  <a href="oldnews_imgs/chrome_win7_jump_list.png">[screenshot]</a>
					</li>
					<li>
						While iTunes is not my primary media player, I still have to use it to sync my iPod and occasionally play music from it when I am creating playlists for my iPod.  One day I did something I do all the time with Windows Media Player 12: I hovered over iTunes on the taskbar when I wanted to change the song.  To my surprise, I saw this: <a href="oldnews_imgs/itunes_win7_thumb_btns.png">[screenshot]</a>  It appears that iTunes 9 has the same thumbnail buttons as WMP12 as well as a jump list with options to open or search the iTunes store.  It does not, however, have WMP's "Play all music" or "Resume last playlist" options, nor does it have a list of frequently played songs/videos/playlists.  Unfortunately iTunes has yet to support Aero Snap properly.
					<br/>
					EDIT: iTunes now sort of supports Aero Snap.
					</li>
					<li>
						Steam just got updated a few days ago (finally) with decent support for Windows 7.  Valve may have waited until the last minute to do this, but they did a pretty nice job.  Steam now has a jump list that can quickly take you to a certain tab (Store, My Games, News, Community, or Friends), allow you to set your status (Online, Away, Busy, or Offline), or start a recently played game.  You can also pin games.  Here is a picture of it: <a href="oldnews_imgs/steam_win7_jump_list.png">[screenshot]</a>  One other feature that was added that I have not seen in any other program but Windows Explorer is having the taskbar icon double as a loading bar when you are downloading or updating a game <a href="oldnews_imgs/steam_win7_loading_bar.png">[screenshot]</a>  Unfortunately, Steam still has no support for Aero Snap.
					</li>
				</ul>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2009 15:35:22 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Apology + Update + Rant: I think I am missing something here...</title>
			<link>http://zmyaro.com/blog/post.html#2009-10-20</link>
			<description>
				<b>2009-10-20:</b> Apology + Update + Rant: I Think I Am Missing Something Here...
				<br/>
				<br/>
				Sorry about not doing much here recently.  Been busy with other stuff (school, inProd, a little gaming if I ever have a free moment (which does not happen often thanks to the first two)).  I can tell you that at inProd, we are working on something really awesome.  I cannot give any details, but trust me, you are really going to like it.  I have also finished some nice updates to the <a href="http://inprod.co">inProd website</a> and my <a href="comp/school/math/index.html">math-on-computer tutorials</a> section (which I hope to expand at some point to general school-on-computer topics).
				<br/>
				<br/>
				Anyway, now that I have explained why I have not updated the site in so long, I thought I might rant for a little.  I actually have a few rants that I will hopefully post some time soon (assuming I have another few minutes of free time), but I decided put up this one since we are about two months (give or take depending on where you live) into the school year and are once again dealing with good, not-so-good, and just plain bad classes and teachers.  Please note that many of my rants are written so that there will be some disagreement.  I will try to put up pages for comments.  Unfortunately, this will only be open to Google Wave users.  Anyway, here we go...
				<br/>
				<br/>
				This is how school works: You ride a bus to a (relatively) big building.  You go to a room full of desks and chairs and learn information from a teacher.  At various points during the day, you might go to a different room, also filled with desks and chairs, and learn things from a different teacher.  After several hours of this, you leave the building, get on a bus again, and go home.  At least, that is how school os <i>supposed</i> to work.  How does school not follow that?  That minor detail of "...and learn information from a teacher."  For some reason, it seems like few teachers actually <i>teach</i>.  And of those who do, many of them show signs that seem to indicate that they do not do their jobs very well.  Let me explain by going through a few classes I am taking or have taken.
				<a href="oldnews.html#2009-10-20">Read more...</a>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2009 22:24:21 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>News: I will be away for a month</title>
			<link>http://zmyaro.com/blog/post.html#2009-07-23</link>
			<description>Starting on 07-28-09, I will be away for almost a month without my computer and probably without Internet. This of course means that I will not be updating the website or responding to e-mails. The site, however, will still be up. Just wanted to let you know!</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2009 22:33:53 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Some random comments with a bit of news thrown in</title>
			<link>http://zmyaro.com/blog/post.html#2009-07-21</link>
			<description>
				<ul>
					<li>
						Why is it that while sites like Google, Ask.com, and Wikipedia, as well as some other smaller, lesser-known sites have at minimum special pages to be viewed on mobile devices and in some cases, different buttons, images, and page formatting (and sometimes JavaScript) specifically designed for the iPhone and iPod touch, but Apple's website (the site belonging to the company that <i>made</i> the iPhone) is not designed at all for compatibility with the iPhone?
					</li>
					<li>
						Why is it that <i>The Journeyman Project: Turbo</i> and <i>The Journeyman Project 2: Buried In Time</i>, two games designed for Windows 3.1 and Windows 95, do not work on Windows XP but work on Windows 7 (RC) without compatibility mode?  Yes, this is true.  I discovered it today.  Please let me know if you know how to get either of these games to run on XP.
					</li>
				</ul>
				In other news, I plan to upload some stuff in the "Video Games" section of my site.  Please not that this has not been update for many months, but I figured that I might as well use the rest of my webspace (all nine megabytes of it).
			</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2009 22:54:44 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>News: arena_courtyard comes as a surprise</title>
			<link>http://zmyaro.com/blog/post.html#2009-07-17</link>
			<description>A friend of mine created a map for <i>Team Fortress 2</i> (you may remember that I made one a few months ago and recently released an alpha version.  The interesting thing about his map is that he does not own TF2 and built the map in the <i>Portal</i> map editor.  After some--scratch that, a TON--of retexturing and some changes to accomodate the differences in size between Chell and the Heavy in the TF2 map editor on my PC, the map was somewhat playable.  We are now at alpha 5.1 and the map is looking pretty good.  We have not been able to test it on a "real" server (i.e. the best we have had is 1-on-11 over LAN) so we do not know how well the map plays, but it looks like it should work pretty well.  You can see its page on TF2maps.net &lt;http://forums.tf2maps.net/showthread.php?ltr=C&amp;t=8138&gt; or download older versions from <a href="http://sites.google.com/site/zmyaro/files">my Google Site</a>.  Enjoy!</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2009 21:24:10 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>A review of the new <i>Harry Potter</i> movie</title>
			<link>http://zmyaro.com/blog/post.html#2009-07-15</link>
			<description>I saw the new <i>Harry Potter</i> movie this morning (the only reason I woke up before noon).  These are my feelings about it.  I personally thought this was the worst of the books.  The main reason was that it seemed written just to be a movie, and not to be good <i>Harry Potter</i> story.  There was soo much focus on the relationships instead of whatever it is that makes the other books exciting.  Sadly, this was one of the few ways this movie stayed true to the book.  As someone who likes these sort of movies to be true to the books they are based on, I have had complaints about all the <i>Harry Potter</i> movies.  The exclusion of Snape's potion riddle in the first, the exclusion of the deathday party in the second, unnecessary changes in the third and fifth, confusing skips in the fourth, and the exclusion of Hogsmeade from the fifth (just to name a few).  The fourth would probably have been the best, except that it skipped too fast from event to event.  Oh, and that the maze was completely messed up.  Still, I think the first (and second) movie(s) did a great job of bringing the magical world of Harry Potter to life.  The third made a few changes, but was still overall quite good.  They started going downhill from there, though.  For whatever reason, someone at Warner Brothers has something against house elves (which should have been in, but were excluded from the fourth and sixth movies), characters having consistant hair length, and keeping a director.  The fifth almost brought the series back to the level of the third, but now David Yates (director of #5 and #6) has brought the <i>Harry Potter</i> movies back into their decline.  Honestly, I was hating this movie from almost the very start.  I was happy to see them showing the destruction of the bridge, as mentioned in the book (even if that scene seems to have replaced the chapter "The Other Minister"), but the whole train station part was completely random.  It was not in the book and personally I thought the book's version of Dumbledore picking up Harry was much better and funnier.  From the Slughorn scene on, it was good even if some things were changed around a little bit.  My only complaints from then until later were the interactions between Harry and Ginny, the lack of fire and other effects in the Unbreakable Vow scene (I expected the makers of the movie to be HAPPY to have a scene designed for effects like that), and the Borgin and Burkes scene.  Malfoy was supposed to go alone and look at the cabinet, not have some huge ceremony.  From then until later it was fine (except that it should have been Tonks who found Harry).  From then until Christmas, I have no comaplaints except that I would have like to see a scene with Snape teaching.  The Christmas scene, however, was completely messed up.  There was not supposed to be Death Eaters burning the Burrow!  Nor should there have been Harry chasing Bellatrix or Ginny chasing him!  There <i>was</i> supposed to be the Minister of Magic, but I guess they forgot about him (just like they forgot about chapter one).  Later on, I want to know why they added in the scene with Harry and Ginny in the Room of Requirement and removed Griffindor winning the quidditch cup.  Finally, the ending was somewhat disappointing.  The cave was okay (although the last part was overly dramatic), and the part on top of the tower was great, but the ending was FAIL.  They removed Dumbledore's funeral in exchange for people holding up their wands and lighting up the sky for a second?!<br/><br/>I agree with what I was told about the movie before I saw it: if you know nothing about the <i>Harry Potter</i> books and are just seeing it as a movie, then you will enjoy it.  If you are a fan of the series, you will not.<br/><br/>While I know this will probably not happen, I would like to see Chris Columbus (director of the first two movies) come back for the last one.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2009 16:32:52 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>News: Aaaaaaaand we are back!</title>
			<link>http://zmyaro.com/blog/post.html#2009-07-15</link>
			<description>I just wanted to mention that I have updated the RSS feed and plan to resume updating it regularly.  In addition, there is now a page for <a href="oldnews.html">archived news</a>.  After being on my home page for a while or when a more important news post takes its place, a news post will be removed from my home page, however it will remain in the archive forever or until the file and its backups get corrupted or lost or I am forced to remove it from the server, whichever comes first.  In addition, the RSS feed will contain the previous two news posts as well (in case there are any of you on the Internet who only check the feed).</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2009 16:21:37 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>News: Laptop home and TF2 map back online</title>
			<link>http://zmyaro.com/blog/post.html#2009-07-10</link>
			<description>I got my laptop back and as promised I have uploaded my TF2 map (the link is below this paragraph).  Not only that, but the version number has gone up!  To test it, save the file to "C:\Program Files\Steam\steamapps\[yourUserName]\team fortress 2\tf\maps" (replace "Program Files" with "Program Files (x86)" if you have 64-bit) and it will show up under the map drop-down menu in the "Create Server" box in TF2.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2009 16:00:00 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>News: Portal maps and other information</title>
			<link>http://zmyaro.com/blog/post.html#2009-06-29</link>
			<description>I do not have my laptop (I am borrowing someone else's computer to post this update), so I will not be uploading anything new for a little while.  Hopefully I will get around to uploading some (or hopefully all) of the video games section when I get it back.  The main update today (besides letting the Internet know I have not forgotten about my site) is putting a link to my <i>Portal</i> map pack!!!(the link is right below this paragraph)  On a semi-related note, my TF2 map is no longer on the server, but I will finish some improvements I have been making when I get my own laptop back and re-upload the map when that is done.  Umm...I think that is all for now.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2009 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>New home page</title>
			<link>http://zmyaro.com</link>
			<description>A slightly better home page has been uploaded.  There is still not much content, but I promise I will upload some video game stuff when I have time.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2009 19:02:50 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Scorp update</title>
			<link>http://zmyaro.com/star_trek/scorp/index.html</link>
			<description>I have uploaded the new Scorp dictionaries.  They include more words, more translations, and a slightly different layout in the English to Scorp one.</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2009 14:27:20 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Site is back (sort of)</title>
			<link>http://zmyaro.com</link>
			<description>I have a temporary home page uploaded to my new webspace.  Unfortunately, I am now down to 9 MB of free webspace, so that means less content unless I decide to pay money.</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2009 14:53:00 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>No more webspace problem (for now)</title>
			<link>http://zmyaro.com</link>
			<description>I have managed to delete/shrink enough stuff to stay within my webspace limit (for now), so I can once again upload things...including a new version of Olinsky: The Game!</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2008 22:03:47 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Out of Webspace</title>
			<link>http://zmyaro.com</link>
			<description>I am over my webspace limit.  Because of this, I will not be able to upload new stuff for a while.  I have also had to remove Olinsky: The Game from the site for a little while.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2008 11:48:00 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Scorpio page</title>
			<link>http://zmyaro.com/star_trek/scorp/index.html</link>
			<description>I have fixed some problems in my Star Trek section and added a page about the Scorpio (with the dictionaries!).</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2008 17:54:00 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
		<!--<item>
			<title>Olinsky: The Game Demo v1.2</title>
			<link>http://zmyaro.com/vgs/inprod/games/olinsky/index.html</link>
			<description>Demo version 1.2 of Olinsky: The Game has been uploaded.  The only major difference from v1.1 is that Olinsky's name is spelled correctly.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2008 17:00:00 EST</pubDate>
		</item>-->
		<!--<item>
			<title>Olinsky: The Game is online</title>
			<link>http://zmyaro.com/vgs/inprod/games/olinsky/index.html</link>
			<description>I have put Olinsky: The Game on my website.</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2008 17:50:00 EST</pubDate>
		</item>-->
		<item>
			<title>The RSS feed is up!</title>
			<link>http://zmyaro.com</link>
			<description>I have added an RSS feed for my entire website.</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2008 17:41:00 EST</pubDate>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
